<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://uaarg.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://uaarg.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 03:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 03:41:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>

    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 5 - Banquet</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/16/auvsi-day-5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/16/auvsi-day-5</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Uaargians! 
Today marks the final day of the 2018 AUVSI competition before heading back to Washington for some sight seeing. We were finally able to take a rest and sleep in this morning, before arriving back at the field to take the total group photo.  With our plane in many pieces, the only large portion remaining was the wings, so we taped them to the back of Brian for the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/brian_the_uav.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also stayed for lunch and handed in our security tags, and then returned to the college to relax a little while longer. The banquet was at the college, so it was a close walk for us to get there. The banquet was a chance to have one last recap of the competition where the results and awards were handed out. We were even featured in the slide show presentation for our amazing safety demonstration by wearing a hard hat when taking off the plane, as well as Brian and his two hats at the same time. The overall results came in and we were a solid 25th out of the 51 teams that flew and 69 teams that were at the competition – a great achievement considering all the troubles we faced. Although no awards, we were very pleased and proud of our efforts at the competition this year and are looking forward to next year’s competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;transform: rotate(90deg);&quot; src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/cake_cropped.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will spend the next couple days in Washington before heading home for the summer until school starts back up again. That is all from the competition this year, so I hope you enjoyed it! See ya later UAARG nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/everyone.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 4 - Flight Day</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/15/auvsi-day-4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/15/auvsi-day-4</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Uaargites, 
Today is the day of our flight! We woke up early today to get to the base and eat breakfast. The majority of the morning was spent setting up all of the equipment and making adjustments to the flight plan. A highlight of our set up was the cardboard boxes we cut to put the laptops in in order to block the sunlight; very high tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/cardboard.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next few hours were just spent waiting for our number to be called and making any minor adjustments, as well as going through our check lists and testing all our equipment. Finally, after a few hours of waiting it was on to group 38. We loaded our plane and equipment into the trailer that came for us and hopped on to be taken out to the runway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/alive_plane.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick debrief from the judges and a meeting of our flight plan and we went straight into setting up our booth, getting ready to be called to fly. Weilan and Ryan were set up to control the imaging, Dat and Janay were doing the autopilot, Jackie threw the plane and then came back to help with support at the tent, and Matthew and Brian were on the runway with Brian ready to take over the manual flight if necessary. Unfortunately, upon the initial takeoff, the plane did not have enough power as the motor was not assembled properly and the plane took a dive back into the ground smashing the nose. This was not enough to stop us, and we all rushed together to begin the repairs. With limited time and parts, we completely took apart the airframe. The first issue was to fix the nose using lots of duct tape and to secure the camera inside. A secondary issue that came up was the tail rudder was not moving, so we pulled apart and tested all the wires, but discovered that the servos was broken. We completely re-installed this part as well as a large portion of the frame. With seconds to spare, we took off for a second time – this time successfully – however began experiencing problems with the autopilot connection and were forced to land the plane to further troubleshoot the error. We found that the signal receptor was falling out of place due to bent prongs going into the circuit board, so we straightened these and re-installed the receptor. As well, the landing pulled off the tail, so we wrapped the back wing in duct tape to fasten the two parts together. We were able to send the plane up one final time and achieved the target of having 3 minutes of autonomous flight before switching back to manual mode, but again encountered signal problems – this time completely losing signal. The lost signal enacted the fail safe and the plane went down for the final time, completely shattering many of the pieces. Although a failed mission, it was an incredible experience to have banded together and gotten the plane back in the air multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/dead_plane.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following our flight, we returned to the college and went for supper to a Japanese Hibachi restaurant. The rest of the night was spent was spent relaxing and playing card games, and finally getting some much-needed sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/sleeping_matt.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is the final day of the competition with the group photo and the banquet taking place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 3</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/14/auvsi-day-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/14/auvsi-day-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello UAARG nation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up early today as it was the first official day of flying at the competition. We arrived at the military base around 7 to sign in and get our personal escort to where we will be set up for the next few days. A quick breakfast and it was on to the preliminary safety checks before flight. We were ordered 38th in the competition so we were not going to fly today but wanted to get all our initial set up done to ensure everything was going according to plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/setup.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few hiccups came along with the fail-safe, but they got worked out and we were all set for when we get called to fly. The rest of our time at the base today was spent doing more setup and getting prepared to fly including testing the camera and making Ryan walk far from the booth for the right distance, before going back to the college shortly after lunch. When we arrived back at the dorm, it was the beginning of working out the flight plan for the flight and planning some of the specifics. A quick nap for a tired Jackie and many lemon cookies for Dat were key in re-energizing and planning our trek to the ocean for seafood dinner. A lovely traffic jam led to a seaside adventure, filled with softshell crab straight from the ocean – almost all the crab the restaurant had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/walk.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After dinner, in search of a lighthouse, we discovered that the light house was the name of a restaurant… but that didn’t halt our fun and we discovered a marina filled with boats- some of which Weilon hit while skipping rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/seaside.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was the end of the peninsula the college and base were located on for a romantic sunset watch and walk on the beach – just one of the many great perks of being part of the UAARG nation. Being driven out by mosquitos, we made our way back to the college and continued work on the flight plan and other tasks, and then off to bed, except for the fearless Janay who stayed up all night working. Tomorrow will be the second day of flying, and hopefully our turn to test our project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/sunset.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 2</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/13/auvsi-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/13/auvsi-day-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks the official start of the competition. We awoke to another lack of water and strong hunger, but it was set aside to begin the preparation for the competition. We then all piled into the van to go for lunch and finally, and democratically, settled on a noodle restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/noodles.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next destination was Wal-Mart to get water and snacks for the week, as well as a fire extinguisher for the competition. More work for setting up and we were off to the fire hall for registration and the kick off. There was a long wait to test the interop server but finally we were able to successfully test, just in time for the announcement of the order of flying. Of the 69 teams registered, 51 were flying in the competition and we were in the top 15 to pick which spot we wanted to fly in, which was based on the ranking of our preliminary reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/orientation.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We diligently strategized and settled on spot 38 to test our plane. Then it was back to the college for more work which included assembling the plane and trying to work out the remaining kinks with regards to the autopilot and imaging. A few hours spent doing this, and a few calls to Rijesh and Sebastien, and it we called it a night. Tomorrow is the first day of flying as well as all the safety testing to ensure everything is working, but so far so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 1</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/12/auvsi-day-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2018/06/12/auvsi-day-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/airport.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a long night and following day spent packing and travelling to the airport, we all met up in Toronto - minus Jackie – where we began the second leg of the journey on the way to Washington. A very tired group, having been up all night in Edmonton, was very relieved to have made it to the end of the flying portion of the travel, meeting Jackie in Washington who was flying in from San Antonio, all with our safety captain Weilon wearing our sturdy hard hat. Remember, safety first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/hardhat.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then proceeded to get a minivan and a car from the rental place, and hit the road in search of food, which brought Vietnamese subs and soup with too few noodles. After being fed, it was on to St. Mary’s College of Maryland where we will be staying for the next few days during competition. We were finally on our way and nothing was going to slow us down, except for a few too many wrong turns. The long and tiresome journey finally came to an end and we arrived at the college, ready to check in and relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our discovery of a lack of water however proved to be far from relaxing, taking us to extreme measures in search of this. Stumbling across a vending machine that only accepts 1 dollar bills and change threw us for a loop… but it was no match for our fearless leader Brian – with the help of some found change in the machine – and we successfully survived our first chaotic experience. A quick game of Settlers of Catan between Jackie and Dat and we were ready for sleep, after some 30 hours of being awake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2018/wave.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 3</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2017/06/16/auvsi-day-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2017/06/16/auvsi-day-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flight day is here! We left the hotel and arrived on site at around 7am. We were not sure what time we would be flying so we made sure we were there first thing in the morning. When we got there, we saw that our flight time would be happnening later during the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gave us even more time to make some more last minute preparations for the flight. It had gotten pretty windy during the day, so we modified the flight plan to compensate for wind speeds. We also triple inspected the airframe assembly and fully charged the battery again, just to be extra sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was some downtime between us finishing the setup preparations and our flight time, so we decided to talk to some other teams and watch some other flights. There were a couple flights that had crashed, and luckily that wasn’t the case for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once our flight time came, we loaded our equipment for the flight onto the cart and were shipped off towards the flight area. When we arrived at the pits, we were given 20 minutes to set up our equipment and be ready to take-off. Once we had linked into the interoperability server, we then received the locations of the stationary flight obstacles and saw that our flight plan had us fly through 2 of them. We then quickly modified our flight plan to try to avoid them where we could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/Setup_Day3.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plane Setup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, with the use of our handy-dandy safety and flight checklists, we finished the set-up well within the time given. We then gave our mission briefing to the judges, led by our very own fantastic team leader and co-president, Sebastian, where he described our systems, mission plan, and member roles to the judges before we flew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ground-station we were using at the flight area looked directly into the flight zone towards the direction of the launch, keeping our little Jownsey and the field team in sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/Field.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Field Team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all members of the flight line took their positions, Sebastian initiated the check in sequence. “Imaging station is ready” said Cindy breaking the suspense, “auto-pilot is ready to go, engaging take off sequence” Sebastian said as the fierce humming of the propeller reached the ground-station. With two delicate hops forward, Andrew threw Jownsey with gentle elegance. Autonomous take off was a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this point, Jownsey was far out of the ground stations field of view and would be monitored and directed from the ground control station. Jownsey circled the skies at an altitude of 120 meters above sea level in preparation to tackle his first task. Once sufficient altitude was reached, Jownsey cruised at a speed of 15 m/s northbound to capture the initial way-points, which surrounded a stationary obstacle. Jownsey skillfully swooped around the obstacle in a U-shape, capturing all the waypoints and avoiding the obstacle completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All was well and quiet until the GPS signal began to flutter. Suddenly, the GPS indicator on the ground control station flashed into a bright red, signaling that Jownsey has lost connection to the GPS, thus rendering him completely blind to his current position. If the connection couldn’t be regained, Rijesh would have been forced to manually take control of Jownsey, putting a halt to our mission. Luckily, lights flashed back to green after a few moments, and Jownsey resumes his original course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/Ground_Station.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ground Station&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we neared the end of our search, the camera feed to the imaging station cut off. A connection within the onboard camera had been severed, but conveniently we obtained all the photos we needed. Jownsey was then rerouted back towards the north as it initiated its south-bound landing sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Covering around half the field, Jownsey descended gradually to around 15 meters above ground level. The elevation reading on the Ground Control Station suddenly indicated that we were 15 meters below the target elevation. At the same moment, Rijesh called in from the field. “Uuhh, is this supposed to be happening? I’m going to attempt to land it manually.” Due to a miniscule error in the autopilot system, Jownsey diverted from the landing path at the last minute. However, with a timely manual take over, Jownsey landed safely with but a small bruise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we recovered Jownsey and brought him back to the ground station, Cindy quickly finished processing the images and we started packing everything away. We managed to end our mission with good time, finishing at 41 minutes exactly. After this the judges gave us their thoughts and feedback on our performance during the flight test. They congratulated and praised us all around, but mainly they complemented us on our team communication and our amazing safety protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a step into the eyes of Jownsey below with these lovely images taken by Jownsey during the competition flight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/Imaging1.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Star-shaped object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/Imaging2.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red semicircle, and what we think is the emergency target on the right side of the image, on the runway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/Imaging3.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some nice broccoli trees, and another target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/Imaging4.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better shot of what we think is the emergent target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/Imaging5.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rijesh, Andrew and Dat can be seen on the bottom right on the runway here(They’re the little dots).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of our flight will be coming out this evening, so stay tuned for updates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dat and Jackie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 2</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2017/06/15/auvsi-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2017/06/15/auvsi-day-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was mainly our flight preparation day. We passed through the safety inspection very cleanly and without any trouble. Due to our brilliant flight time slot chosen by our amazing duo co-presidents, we knew that there was little chance of us getting sent to fly today. This gave us the chance to perfect our preparations. We were able to assemble and inspect our airframe and test our systems while we were at the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/SafetyInspection.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issues we encountered were few in number. The slimmed down travel crate for the plane not only had a smaller frame, but it also brought along with it less damage, where the biggest problem was a slightly bent rudder edge and a nut that came loose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the airframe software, we were thrown for a loop when the waypoints for the interop server were actually located at the firehouse where the briefing was held. We were expecting them to be at the field where we were to be flying so you can imagine how this sent us into a stall. We also had to do some bug extermination, and we dont’t mean the ones in the field(It was actually very well kept).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/AirframeSetup.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather has been amazing these last few days, not very hot and not very cool(just like our airframe team, Ooooooo), so it looks like we have a good chance of flying in nice weather tommorow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the great weather, we (being the engineers we are) decided to leave the field early since we knew we weren’t flying today and instead retreated to the cold air conditioned safety of our wifi connected hotel room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just finished our team flight briefing, completely laying out our game plan and team task delegations. With that we are done with the main preparations for our flight tommorow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/TeamPicDay2.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea of tomorrow’s events, here’s the scenario:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lone hiker, daring to challenge the forces of nature, has wandered too far into the wilderness for his own good. Lost and hungry, he wanders aimlessly through the woods seeking signs of civilization and awaiting rescue. Jownsey must soar through the skies following the tracks of the lost hiker and stalk the Webster Fields to rescue him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules of the mission demonstration are simple, every team is given 20 minutes to setup, were the last 5 minutes must be used to brief the judges of the mission plan. Once the airspace is cleared of any other teams, and the 20 minutes of suspenseful setup has passed, the mission will begin! Points will be given to us based on the reliability of Jownsey’s autonomous flight, its ability to avoid obstacles, and object detection capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will Jownsey successfully rescue the lost hiker? Stay tuned for more updates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dat and Jackie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 1</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2017/06/14/auvsi-day-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2017/06/14/auvsi-day-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some flights and driving, Rijesh, Sebastian, Andrew, Cindy, Brian, Jackie and I have all arrived safely to Lexington Park, Maryland for the 2017 AUVSI UAS Competition. It was a perilous journey, but through it all we persevered and made it to our destination in the land of the free. We embarked on our journey in the dead of the night, having arrived for our flight around 3:00am. Although our members were separated during the flights, had to sit separated and heartbroken, we stayed strong and kept the team spirit burning. After the flights, we then continued our way via car. We rented out two cars for the team and this is where we met the most near-mishaps. During the first long car ride, we nearly lost half the team as Andrew took a wrong turn and nearly got lost on the to the Hotel in Fairfax, Virginia. On the second car trip to Lexington Park, Maryland this almost happened again, but this time it was Rijesh who had taken the wrong turn. But somehow, we made it through all of that and the whole team made it to our hotel in Lexington Park, safe and accounted for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/dat_sleep.gif&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/sebastian_yawn.gif&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We mini-sized our crate for this year compared to last and made it out of the oversized baggage category. Its taken on a new diet plan and slimmed down; we cut packing peanuts out of its diet and replaced them with bubble wrap instead. As you can see, it was a very effective diet plan and we would recommend it to all those other crates looking to slim down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/new_crate.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the competition briefing today, we found out that the competition this year has 44 teams! This is significantly more than the 24 teams that were present last year; a truly daunting challenge indeed. We also received the feedback for our journal paper and our Flight Readiness Review Video, and it was quite good. This has only made our team even more pumped up and raring for the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to last year, where we were given our flight order; this year, we got to choose our order to fly. From the moment we found out about this, our co-presidents, Sebastian and Rijesh, instantly went into extremely intense deliberation. Having considered various factors, ranging from team readiness, flight preparation, future weather conditions, and team distribution by day, they had decided on us being the 33rd team to fly. With this wise and calculated decision, our co-presidents have brought to us an amazing flight time slot, bringing an end to the briefing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2017/sebastian_place.gif&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, we’ll be doing our safety inspection for the plane and making some more preparations for the flight, with a light chance of flying. Then on Friday, we’ll be sending our own little Jownsey (That’s the name of the plane) into the air for the competition flight. This blog will be updated and filled with our completion adventures during the next few days so make sure to stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 4 - Final</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/16/auvsi-day-4-final.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/16/auvsi-day-4-final</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We performed our competition flight today. We had a catastrophic crash; read on for more details about that. Here are some nice photos from before the crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/assembled-plane.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/loaded-gator.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crashed shortly after takeoff; after performing a manual takeoff, going into auto-stabilized flight mode, then going into fully autonomous flight, the aircraft began maneuvering out of control.
Rijesh attempted to manually recover the aircraft, but it was too late by that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some photos of the debris; unfortunately we don’t have any other recovered photos (including from the plane’s camera) that show what happened during the crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/full-wreckage.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/detached-motor.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/crashed-batteries.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/wreckage-on-gator.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/wreckage-close.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hypotheses on what caused the crash, after looking at the debris and the logs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Poor wing alignment due to taking off and putting the wings back on at the flight line.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overspeed on the approach into the standby circle, due to the use of a new propeller with a different pitch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We noticed that the elevator had ripped off and had landed away from the other debris; we think that the elevator may have ripped off when the plane was approaching standby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all just hypotheses; further testing is required to determine which one of these was the likeliest cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final stats on overall team performance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;43 teams initially registered in this competition.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30 teams submitted journal papers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;24 teams successfully submitted the required safety pilot flight logs, proof of telemetry upload to the interoperaility server, and the proof of flight video.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;24 teams passed the Flight Readiness Review and safety inspection and were able to fly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We obtained an overall ranking of 16, out of the 30 teams that submitted journal papers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We obtained a mission rank of 5, journal rank of 14, and a rank of 19 for our Flight Readiness Review. 
We tied for 5th on mission rank with a lot of other teams because we failed to meet the interoperability requirement for confirming that we successfully reached a flight waypoint.
This is because we did not fly far enough to successfully reach a waypoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/results.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank the University of Alberta’s Faculty of Engineering, the Shell Enhanced Learning Fund, and the University of Alberta’s Students’ Union for helping to fund us over the past year and for this competition. We’d also like to thank Cameron Lee for his unwavering support, dedication, and advice over the past few years. Finally, we would like to thank our faculty advisors, Dr. Duncan Elliott and Dr. Michael Lipsett for their support of the club. We received some good advice from the judges on what to improve for next year’s competition and took note of the good practices from all the teams we met at competition, and are looking forward to doing better next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 3</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/16/auvsi-day-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/16/auvsi-day-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we waited all day. The order of flights is random, and the order is
drawn on the fly. Therefore, we always have to remain ready for flights, but
don’t know when our flight actually will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know, however, that we are the 5th team flying tomorrow (we are told this
in order to ensure that we show up at the correct time). In the meantime, here
are some nice photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/tarmac-teams.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teams getting ready to be transported to the flight line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/mag-calibration.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rijesh, Sebastian, and Andrew performing a magnetometer calibration. This is
important for correctly obtaining the yaw of the aircraft, which is important for geolocating images. Standing on one leg, as Andrew is doing, is not required for this calibration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/desu.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnathan, assisting with the magnetometer calibration as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/elevator-inspection.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnathan and Rijesh inspecting the aircraft’s elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/flight-plan.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jorge and Sebastian inspecting the autopilot flight plan. They did a lot of
simulations today to verify the behaviour of the aircraft with different waypoint
configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/encouragement.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rijesh giving Andrew some much-needed encouragement. Andrew is working on putting
our autopilot telemetry data, such as GPS coordinates, into the metadata of the
images we capture, rather than in a separate file. This task has left him very
downtrodden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try to get a blog post out tomorrow afternoon, after our flight. Stay tuned
for the results!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 2</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/16/auvsi-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/16/auvsi-day-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed our safety inspection and Flight Readiness Review presentation today. The weather for the next few days won’t be great - there are heavy rains coming tomorrow and more potentially on Saturday.
There was a chance for teams to fly today in the afternoon; however, we didn’t take it as our systems weren’t ready at the time. 
Only 3/24 teams flew today; it is likely that the Sunday rain day will be used with the current forecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also tested our interoperability systems today - both the telemetry and target information update to the judges’ servers worked beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues we encountered today included;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trouble with updating the autopilot flight plan for this year’s competition waypoints.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixing a cracked tail servo.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An unreliable serial data line from the autopilot telemetry port to the onboard imaging computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been able to resolve 2/3 of these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/andrew-plane.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew looking chipper with a partially assembled plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we’ll be able to get a flight in soon. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 1</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/15/auvsi-day-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/15/auvsi-day-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rijesh, Jorge, Sebastian, Johnathan, Andrew, and I have arrived safely in Lexington Park, Maryland for the 2016 AUVSI Student UAS Competition.
This will be a quick update, as the only competition event today was the team check-in and briefing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/crate.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plane in the crate, VERY nicely packed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned today at the briefing that out of the 46 teams originally registered, only 24 teams (including, of course, us) made it to competition.
Only ~30 teams managed to submit a journal paper, and more teams dropped off during the checks for a proof of flight video and proof of interfacing with the interoperability server.
This is significantly less teams than were present last year (30); we feel good about being one of the teams that successfully passed the increased requirements for this year's competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schedule for the next few days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thursday, June 16th - Flight Readiness Review and Safety Inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friday, June 17th and Saturday, June 18th - Competition flights. The weather forecast for Friday indicates thunderstorms, so flights will most likely have to occur all the way to late Saturday afternoon.
Saturday is also the date of the competition banquet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sunday, June 19th - Rain day (spillover for competition flights). Which might have to be used.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monday, June 20th - ???&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tuesday, June 21st - Return home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'll keep you updated right here on this blog - stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auvsi2016/wow.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnathan, Jorge, and Sebastian. And Rijesh trying to take photos in peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition Follow Up and Getting Ready For US Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/13/getting-ready-for-auvsi-2016.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/06/13/getting-ready-for-auvsi-2016</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are right now getting ready for US competition. We will be leaving tommorrow and will be blogging all about it here at uaarg.com. Stay tuned for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a wrap up to canadian competition: we placed 7th out of the 14 teams. We need to improve our imaging system a bit more to get some clearer photos and better georeferencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another note here are a bunch of pictures in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_01.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_02.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_03.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_04.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_05.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_06.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_07.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_08.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_09.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_10.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_11.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_12.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_13.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_14.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_15.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_16.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_17.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_18.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cancomp2016/cancomp_batch_19.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition 2016 Day 3</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/05/01/day3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/05/01/day3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We performed our last competition flight. As a treat there is a video at the end showing take off and landing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were given 1hr to generate a report of the flight. Everyone you see below is busy generating the report. Everyone else was having enough free time to take the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/busyworking.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shout-out to Jorge for organizing the report generation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Target areas were superimposed onto a map of the search area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/map2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final results will be made known to us tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the vido on our youtube &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pYc_00_9lgI&quot;&gt;channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition 2016 Day 2</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/04/30/day2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/04/30/day2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first competition flight happend today. I was scheduled for 8:30am so we woke up bright and early for setup. It ended up getting pushed back to ~9:15am. This allowed for a great photo-op.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gangsters.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the flight actually happened Jorge manned autopilot while Dylan monitored imaging. Our autopilot was preprogrammed so apart from initiallizing the search area routine, these two folks made sure the plane was operating properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/monitoring.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rijesh and Dat spent there time on the runway chilling. Rijesh only has to fly the plane for landing and takeoff. The rest of the time Dat and him were playing spot the moving spec in the sky. Visual contact at the range is made by competition observers to ensure that the UAV stays within bounds. The UAV flew ~1.9km from the ground control station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chilling.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight went swimingly. Our actual flight path is shown below and can be contrasted with the simulated one from yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/compday2real.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve made a few tweaks to the autopilot based on data we got back from the flight. These changes have been implemented for tommorrow’s final competition flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imaging preformed okay. We seem to have been a little out of focus and were experiencing the occasional motion blur. We did manage to cover the entire search area and have some sort of image for each crop target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/can2016target.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have another flight tommorrow at 8am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally here is a picture of Brian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brian.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition 2016 Day 1</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/04/29/day1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/04/29/day1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we had our system presentation. It was esentially a faux pitch to an agricultural client. The presentation went well and the lead presentation judge mentioned in passing that he liked our presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition we had our flight readiness review. This review is where we prove that we are able to operate our plane safely. This again went exceedingly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016frr.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we had time to do a test flight. Takeoff, flight, automatic control, imaging and landing all went off without a hitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016work.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything looks well for tommorrow’s competition flight. Below is a simulated survey path for our UAV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/can_2016_sim.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit late tonight, but I promise plenty of pictures tommorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition 2016 Day 0</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/04/28/on-the-road.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/04/28/on-the-road</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick update. Today we are on our way to Southport, Manitoba. The weather looks good. Not much traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loaded_van.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We packed everything in our vehicles yesterday allowing for an early start today. The trip is just over 1200km so we expect to arrive by around 10pm, stopping at an Arby’s or two along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is looking good. Test flights were carried out yesterday and the preceding day. Autopilot should be able to meet the long distance survey tasks and imaging systems should operate as required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tommorrow we will have our system presentation and flight readiness review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk to you later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition 2016</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2016/04/19/getting-ready-comp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2016/04/19/getting-ready-comp</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are busy getting ready for Canadian Competition this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition will take place between April 29th and May 1st. We will keep you updated on our progress here.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 3 Performance and Results</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/06/20/auvsi-competition-day-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/06/20/auvsi-competition-day-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competition Day 3 has arrived and past. Yesterday we found out that we were team number 31 of 32 for flying. That meant that our flight time would be early in the morning. Big shout out to our base access liason, Brendan. He allowed us to store some equipment in his truck the day before, allowing us to keep our plane ready for launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/compplane.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the flight time and prepped our plane for launch. Our mission time started at 8:53am. Each member of the team had a specific role. Rijesh was the flight commander, Cindy was the imaging technician, Sebastian was the autopilot technician and Brian was the telemetry technician. Rijesh is also usually our safety pilot, but this competition does provide pilots. The safety pilot was fully debriefed beforehand on the workings of the UAV, autopilot controls, and failsafes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/working.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Mission Time#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the start of mission time we brought the plane into launch configuration in a little less than 3 minutes. This involved powering up the plane, establishing a telemetry link, establishing a Wi-Fi link, performing camera exposure and focus lock, installing the camera and engaging our image capture software. During this time Cindy and Sebastian set up the software portions of imaging and autopilot respectively. Rijesh was busy turning on the plane and configuring the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point the plane was ready for launch. Rijesh hand launched the plane and the safety pilot put the plane at 130m above the ground. Autonomous flight was engaged at this point. The plane did a 1/2 circle of a standby waypoint and proceeded to perform the autonomous waypoint navigation. This portion of the mission involves the plane flying to different waypoints autonomously. there are 6 different waypoints at varying altitudes. The autopilot performed this task admirably. Yea Autopilot lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next came the autonomous search area navigation. This task involves the plane autonomously performing a search pattern over a search area, while capturing images of the ground. The autopilot again excelled at this task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/flightplan.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight Plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/path.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight Path&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next two tasks that were attempted were the Off axis target task and emergent target. The off axis target is looking for a target that is outside the operational area. This task was attempted by circling a waypoint near the edge of the operational area at increasing altitudes. We did not find this target. The emergent task involves being given a waypoint at the start of mission time and being able to have the plane autonomously navigate to this target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plane was then landed in autonomous mode and the 900 MHz link was turned off. In total ~23 minutes of mission time had elapsed out of our maximum of 40 minutes. Less than 30 minutes of mission time = Bonus Points!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Post Processing#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right before takeoff we lost our Wi-Fi communication link with the plane. This link is designed to transfer images to our ground imaging station for immeadiate processing. As a result all of our image processing had to be done after the plane had landed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/commandtent.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images were then transferred onto ground station computers. Our ground imaging station software is not fully functional so a manual export had to be preformed. Rijesh and Cindy went through the photos reading out load the image number, and target description whenever they found a target. The next step was to manual insert the GPS data for each target. We found all 8 targets. Yay imaging lead!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/target.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brian_on_trailer.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Results#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition is scored based on three different areas. A Journal Paper, a Flight Readiness Review and the Flight-Mission Demo. In total 55 teams had registered and had plans to display their unmanned aerial systems (UAS). Teams from around the world, including Turkey, Israel, India and Romania, participated. Of those 55 teams only 39 completed the Journal Papers. Of those 39 only 32 participated in the Flight-Mission Demo. UAARG placed 18th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journal Paper is a technical paper detailing the design and testing of our UAS. Andrew, Rijesh and Cindy were the primary authors of this paper. In the feedback they let us know that they really liked the parts Andrew had written. They recommended more information on testing. We placed 23 of 39.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Flight Readiness Review is a briefing that is used to show the judges that a team is ready and prepared to fly. Again they recommended that we provide more information on testing. We placed 28 of 34.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how did we get 18? Well our Flight-Mission Demo went really well. This area is where teams actually give a demonstration of there system. Autopilot-wise the system performed admirably. The plane passed over each waypoint and was within 7m of the target waypoint alitude. Shout out to Sebastian for setting up our stellar flight plan. Our Imaging system ran throughout the flight and we were able to capture images of the entire search area. We placed 11th out of 32 teams in actual flight performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Future#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Autopilot we are looking into autonomous takeoff and landing. As well we are looking into incorporating better altitude control loops for wind conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Imaging we want to implement an external magnetometer away from current carrying wires to improve compass heading. We also want to do further tests on image capture and autopilot tagging lag. As well our Ground Imaging Station software needs to be improved so that it can be incorporated into our workflow. In reviewing the pictures we actually found the emergent target. Unfortunately we didn’t recognize it. Due to our software limitations we were not able to have both imaging operators look at all the images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/emerge.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boo Imaging lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Communications we need to improve on establishing and maintaing Wi-Fi data links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Conclusion#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall our performance was very well, especially if you consider the manpower and number of individuals who participated in autopilot and imaging. We’d like to thank everyone for making this such a success. This includes our faculty advisors Duncan Elliott and Michael Lipsett for all the time they spend with us. Peter Cary our safety pilot and airframe advisor. Cameron Lee for all his help in imaging, advising us on best practices, and staying with the club even after graduation. We would also like to thanks Joseph Patton for all his help in the airframe department and all his many other contributions.  We would also like to thank the University of Alberta and Shell Canada for all of the support they have provided.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 2 - The Long Wait</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/06/20/auvsi-competition-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/06/20/auvsi-competition-day-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/suas_pit_area.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another early morning and another long wait. Today we got up at 7 am, slightly later than yesterday. Breakfast would be served at the competition, so we mainly didn’t concentrate on eating breakfast in the hotel. We left and managed to arrive at the gate at 8:25 am and started to setup for our flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took only a few hours to set up and we waited to be called to the flight line. Initially the competition hosts had a list of 12 teams with flight slots; we weren’t on the list but there was a possibility that they would call us to the flight line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition had a queue of 5 teams on the flight line ready to fly at all times. The next few teams that would soon be called out to the flight line would be notified to prepare to head out; the teams would be chosen at random. If any of the teams called a time out, they would move to the back of the line of all the teams that had not flown. The next team after would then be up to fly. So because of this, each team on the flight line had to be ready to fly just in case the team before them decided to call a time out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/suas_flight_line.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, we set up our plane to be ready to pack up and take to the flight line at a moment’s notice. As we waited around, we worked more on the competition flight plan and our ground station imaging software. Eventually the 12 team list dwindled down and other teams began getting notices that they would be soon taken out to the flight line. We continued to wait with the UAV assembled and equipment ready to be packed and loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually lunch came around and we got our lunches. Today it was either pulled pork or pulled chicken sandwiches with potato chips and a cookie. Then back to our waiting. Eventually we started to explore and talk with some of the sponsors and other teams. Google, MathWorks, Airware, Garmin, and many other sponsors had set up tents there. Each of us took our turns to explore the area and talk with sponsors about what they did and what cool new projects they were working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015_suas_pit_setup.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time continued to tick on and eventually it got to 5 pm; and there were still flights going on. We were somewhat hungry so we munched on some snakes we had bought on the first day from Walmart. The judges didn’t know if we would be called up. Once the list of 12 teams had been exhausted, teams would be called to the flight line randomly with sufficient notice, so until our time came, we would know when we were up. We discussed our options with Brendan, our Navy liaison, and continued to wait to make sure we were not called up for the day. Eventually we were called and told we were the second last team on the list. It was around 6pm and there were 5 teams on the flight line and around 4 team ahead of us who still had to go the flight line. It was unlikely that we would be called to the flight line. The flying had to stop before 8 pm and each team had 40 minutes of flight time. A little math said that there would still be quite a few teams ahead of us before flying ended. So we started to pack up for the day nice and slowly. Brandon offered to store some of the boxes that we weren’t using overnight for us, which was a great help since we wouldn’t have to pack as much into the van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then headed for dinner which, this time, was at The Noodle Company. The food was really good and fairly well priced. We each enjoyed our own noodle blow that we ordered. After we finished eating we returned to the hotel and did a bit more testing, blog writing and programming. Today however, we managed to go to bed at 11 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 1 Another Long Day</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/06/18/auvsi-competition-day-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/06/18/auvsi-competition-day-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the second of our blog posts on the 2015 AUVSI Student UAS competition. “Hey, remember that long jet lag, the little to no sleep on the plane, and the going to bed at 1 am, well remember to get up early tomorrow,” is what was going thought our brains this morning as the team decided to wake up at 6 am. Breakfast was provided by the hotel so we all had decided we would eat at the hotel before we left. As it turns out, a few of us managed to eat breakfast, but the majority showed up only when the food had disappeared. So some decided to eat some of the sandwiches from the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ontheroad.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With breakfast taken care of in a sense, we packed up and started to make our way to the air field. It was only a 20 minute drive to get there, so not too bad for travel time. On arrival to the gate, we meet up with our liaison, Brendon, who would escort us on and off the base every day that we were there.  We also got our ID badges which we had to return at the end of the day and pick them up again the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a small drive down to a tarmac close to the runway where they had set up a long row of large tents with tables for each of the teams. There were 38 teams attending the competition this year, so lots of cars and lots of people. Our table was close to the parking lot so unloading was quite easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tents.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/parking.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to our table and started to get ready for our safety inspection and flight readiness review briefing. Brandon made sure that we were settled and hung around to learn more about our UAV. The safety inspections were first come first serve, so we didn�t have to worry about time. Our flight redness review, which is a presentation of what our UAV has for system and how it will work, was scheduled for 2pm. It was 8am when we got to the filed so plenty of time. We did some troubleshooting, testing, and planning. During the time we are on base, we weren’t allowed to turn on any transmitters or WiFi routers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/setup1.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/setup2.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually lunch came around and we were all getting hungry. Lunch was provided by the competition and included a sandwich with potato chips. We ate our lunches meanwhile we continued to work on our UAV to make ready for inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/setup3.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We eventually went to do our safety inspection after we made sure that all the codes were properly installed and everything was working properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/inspection.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspection itself went relatively well, there were just a few hiccups, but nothing too major. One particular test was troublesome and we could not get to work. It was connecting to a server provided by the competition hosts, downloading, and uploading data during the flight. Of course we were just testing to make sure it worked but the issue was pretty simple, we could not connect to the server. It was only a secondary objective, so we did not have to complete this objective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/inspection2.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/inspection3.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/inspection4.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition is split into 2 categories of objectives, primary and secondary. Primary objectives we must complete and included autonomous flight, search the area, and find targets on the ground. Secondary objectives were optional to complete and would add to your score. They included identify targets with the UAV still airborne by sending down images, capture an image of a target outside the flight boundary without flying outside the boundary, locate a target close to a set of coordinates given at take-off, sending flight information to a server on the ground provided by the competition hosts, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up was the flight readiness review. The presentation itself was alright, nothing stellar by any accounts. There were quite a few improvements we could have made to the presentation and perhaps some more rehearsals would have made the presentation better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/latestay.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was still the issue with connecting with the server and when other teams left for their hotels, we stayed behind to troubleshoot our problems. We waited for the no transmitting restriction to be lifted before we could start troubleshooting. For around an extra hour or so we remained behind until the server was shut down for the day. We packed and left the field for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/inthevan.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around dinner time, so we drove down the road back to the hotel and looked for some place to eat. There was much debate on what kind of restaurant we should eat at, maybe even go back to the hotel and eat the rest of our sandwiches. Our first stop was Golden Corral but the buffet was too much food, so next a restaurant next door. Turns out it was a bar and not a restaurant. Then more debate. Eventually we stopped at Chipotle to get some burritos and bowls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/roomnight.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made our way back to the hotel room and ate our food. We then started to with some more testing and troubleshooting for connecting to the competition server. We also completed the flight plan for the flight and some more programming for imaging. It was another late night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/roomnight2.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AUVSI SUAS Competition Day 0 The Arrival</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/06/17/auvsi-competition-day-0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/06/17/auvsi-competition-day-0</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first of our blog posts on the 2015 AUVSI Student UAS competition. Today was quite the day. We all got up early in the morning to catch our flights. We all decided to arrive 2 hours before our flight to the US and we just barely made the flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/denver_airport.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First comes the check in, then comes bag security, then comes security, then comes customs at the United States border. So first we had to check in our bags at the airline check in, which wasn’t too bad, just a couple of hundred dollars and you were on your way. Next we brought our checked bags to security specifically for checked bags. We had two oversized crates that had both airframes and tools in them so we had to unpack everything. Security needed to see everything we packed and swab everything. It took some time but we still had plenty of time, so no worries. Next security for passengers. We spent a little bit of time meanwhile all the security personnel huddled together and made a telephone call to see if we could take the batteries with us on the plane. It all worked out and we meet all the regulations, so onto customs. We went through customs before we left Canada. It went pretty smoothly except one of us got held up for some more questioning. Apparently taking two large wooden creates on a plane through customs raises some questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we made the flight with 15 minutes to spare, which in retrospect wasn’t too bad with all the delays we got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, we got on the plane and flew to Denver, where our second fight was delayed. We spent some time in the airport exploring, eating food, and preparing for competition. Our next flight was to Baltimore Washington airport and was fairly uneventful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We landed, got our bags, took a bus to the rental car building, and got our not so much a grand caravan but something similar van. We filled it to the brim with all of our crates and bags, and drove straight to Lexington Park, Maryland… well straight enough.  On our way to Lexington Park, we may have made a wrong turn and went on a detour that took an extra 15 minutes. But we got a lot of pictures on the scenic detour that we did take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/maryland_road_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/maryland_road_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/maryland_road_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/maryland_road_4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to Lexington Park’s volunteer fire department hall at 8:00pm, where the check in for competition was. The competition was being held in Webster Field (of Naval Air Station Patuxent River), so the drive was only an hour and a half. We got all or information, singed some forms, meet up with our liaison for the military base, and were on our way to the grocery store because we needed food. It was past our dinner and we were all hungry, so what better place to get food then Walmart. It was sandwiches, potato chips, and orange juice for dinner tonight. We all still had some time, so we unpacked our suitcases, bags, and competition supplies in to hotel and started work on things for the next morning - presentations, competition objectives, camera and imagery, programming, and logistics. We were disallowed wireless transmission of any kind during the day tomorrow - as teams would be doing their safety inspections and radio frequency checks – so we did have to work out some logistics relating to wired connection of all our systems. All teams were only allowed to turn on their transmitters – radio control, telemetry, and payload Wi-fi alike – during the safety inspection and frequency check. We had to prepare for that short period of time to do a full check of our wireless systems while on site. Finally, we worked on our systems presentation, in which we had to present to a panel of judges our system setup, mission workflow, safety features, and existing system test data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a lot to squeeze in with all the chaos of getting dinner, checking into the hotel, and unpacking; in the end, we all stayed up until 1 am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/packed_van.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition Day 3</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/05/04/Competition-Day-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/05/04/Competition-Day-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Competition Day 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last flight didn’t go very well. We were fully prepared with our new airframe and were rearing to go the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We launched the plane into the air and had a successful ~40 second flight. After which the plane crashed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are unsure as to what the crashed as further investigation needs to be done. The plane was flying fine and in very close range. It started an uncontrollable roll and never recovered. One idea is that perhaps the flaperons weren’t fully turned off. If they were only turned off half way this would have resulted in limited recovery ability. Another possibility is 2.4 GHz interference. Two other teams crashed today due to interference on the 2.4 GHz spectrum, and a few others experienced interference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/can_crashedplane.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was fairly relaxed, with competition photos and packing the plane. We did still submit a report though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/report.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening we attended the awards banquet. UAARG didn’t receive any prizes but the judges/competition organizers had many encouraging things to say and felt we performed well in different aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Northrop Grumman was a big sponsor this year. They are fairly well known for Global Hawks, but make a wide variety of other systems, including their long range Triton system. The company representative there said there were three main things he was impressed with at competition. One of those things was UAARG’s modular design. He really liked our electronics boards. They have a very simple a laid out design. Each board is more or less identical allowing it to be swapped in and out readily. Components can also easily be swapped in and off the board. Yesterday’s fire was a fairly quick and easy fix due our voltage regulators being over rated for there task. As well our planes can swap parts, like wing and tail sections very easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I am fairly impressed with our performance at competition this year. We may not have done well, but our system is a lot more mature and as a team we were able to handle issues as they arose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canteam.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew and Rijesh apparetnly didn’t get the memo that UAARG’s team shirts were safety vests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be the last daily blog post for Canadian Competition. A week or two from now a few more pictures from competition organizers will be posted.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition Day 2</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/05/03/Competition-Day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/05/03/Competition-Day-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Competition Day 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was fairly interesting. Day 2 of competition is the primary flight day. We are given 45 minutes to fly in the search area and another 60 minutes to compile a report of our findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our flight time was at 12:10pm, so the morning was filled with creating a final report template, readying the plane and a bit of programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set up our Ground Control Station(GCS) and were  comfortably waiting. Finally our time came around. We started up the systems and were turning on imaging, when all of a sudden the plane caught fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier that day concern was expressed as to how strongly our voltage regulators were in place. As a result a rubber band was used to additionally secure them.
The only damage was to a single voltage regulator powering our autopilot board. An electrical connection was quickly made so that the autopilot board drew power from the other voltage regulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/burn.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally with 17 minutes of flight time to spare we made it out to the field. Andrew had the plane up in the air and was just about to launch it when we got a no-go. Dirt-bikers had made there way into the airport property. We subsequently had to wait until they were chased off. Our time was paused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dirtbiker.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew launched the plane, but something flew off as it left Andrew’s hand. Worried it was part of the prop or another vital component, Rijesh immediately cut throttle. The plane came down hard and the tail boom snapped again; in the same place as yesterday. Harmless logo stickers that were poorly applied to the plane had flown off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/stickers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up not going into the air. We got our second airframe ready that afternoon and performed all necessary calibrations. We are feeling very confident about tomorrows flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/day3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition Day 1</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/05/02/Competition-Day-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/05/02/Competition-Day-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Competion Day 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was the first day of competition. We got up very early this morning and headed out to the airport. Once there we finished unpacking the plane and started setting up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/day2_1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We gave an oral presentation on our UAV and its capabilities. Andrew stood at the front of the room and presented to everyone. The main points that were highlighted were actionable inteligence from our live imaging link, modular design, and fast deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the Flight Readiness Review. This mostly deals with autopilot and ensuring all the failsafes are reliable. We passed the FRR succesfully and went on to test flights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose for the test flight was to trim our plane. Rijesh took the plane up, trimmed the plane, and tested autopilot. Unfortunately on landing the tail boom snapped. This has occured twice before at the same spot. We need to investigate means of reinforcing the tail boom to prevent this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/day2_2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall we felt very confident with the aircraft’s performance and are excited for tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon we repaired the tail, and the rest of the day we worked on our final report template, and flight plan for tomorrow’s flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/day2_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition Day 0</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/05/01/Competition-Day-0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/05/01/Competition-Day-0</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So yesterday was fun, filled with plenty of travel. The competition takes place in Alma, Quebec. Alma is a small town 3 hours north of Quebec City. To get there we flew from Edmonton to Toronto to Montreal. From Montreal we rented a minivan and drove to Alma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the night before packing the UAV, all peripheral components, spares and repair tools. For this competition we needed to take two flights. As a result we contructed wooden crates to hold the UAV in. The crates were canabalized from old competition crates, but never the less held strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 4:00am yesterday we left the club room and headed to the airport. We got through security just fine and had no issues with the LiPo batteries. We probably won’t be able to say the same for US competiton though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/airplanewing.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finally reached Montreal we caught a cab to the car rental service and headed out from there. The going was very slow in Montreal but the traffic eventually let up and we a had a long windy drive to Alma. Along the way, we worked on our competition presentation, discussed LOTR lore, worried about gas, tried speaking french, and speculated on what the traffic signs meant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally reach Alma close to 11:00pm. We quickly unpacked and found everything unscathed. It was then time for a well deserved sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/andrew.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also check out the article on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engineering.ualberta.ca/NewsEvents/Engineering%20News/2015/April/Aerialroboticsstudentteamcompetinginhighflyingcompetition.aspx&quot;&gt;faculty of engineering website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Redundancy</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/03/09/developing-redundancies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/03/09/developing-redundancies</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi followers. Here’s another quick update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Launcher#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now we are currently in the midst a developing a fully autonomous launching system. Ideally the pilot intervention should only be required during the landing stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Last Semester#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Semester we had some major success on the autopilot front. We were able to achieve fully autonomous flight. The following are screenshots from google earth showing the path of the plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auto2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/auto3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further tuning needs to be performed as well as incorporation of airspeed data.
Stay Tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Redundancies#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We currently have one working plane. We are hoping to have three up and running planes. That involves modifying two more airframes, assembling two more electronics boards, loading up and configuring imaging computers, and pairing autopilot control boards with various modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of work ahead of us. The goal is to get a second plane ready by the end of March.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>January Update</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/01/25/january-update.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/01/25/january-update</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey world out there. We have been a bit slacking in updating our blog, hopefully that will change for this semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Highlights from last semester:#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Plane - If you recall shortly before US competition our plane had a fateful water landing. During the summer plans were set for our new plane. We have decided to continue using the EPP foam airframe that last year’s capstone group had developed. In the first two weeks of school Andrew, Cindy and Rijesh were busy busy putting the plane together. Andrew made all the modifications and assemebled the airframe, Cindy did her usual imaging magic, and Rijesh brought the electronics and autopilot all together. Our first flight was a success! (see below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fully Autonomous Flight - On our aircrafts maiden flight, we managed to get the plane to a fully autonomous state. The plane successfully navigated through three different waypoints on either side of the flying field, changing altitude by to 200m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kick-off Meeting - We held our annual kick off meeting. We had many people attend and the club room was quite packed last semester. We are hoping that will be the same for this semester as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#The Coming Semester#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have many projects planned for this semester. I’ll try to detail more of what we are doing in the coming weeks as well as the status of our system.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A new site for UAARG</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/07/22/new-site.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/07/22/new-site</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new site for the U of A Aerial Robotics Group, now hosted on Github Pages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the content from our old blog will be migrated over soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-examples-of-formatting&quot;&gt;Some examples of formatting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import math

sine_list = []
for i in range(19):
    sine_list.append(math.sin(i)     
print(sine_list)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two crashes and rethinking the plane</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/06/21/two-crashes-and-rethinking-plane.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/06/21/two-crashes-and-rethinking-plane</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello from the AUVSI Student UAS competition! The 4 of us – Joe, Paul, Cindy, and Rijesh – are currently in Lexington Park, Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have heard, we had some show-stopping events just before the AUVSI competition. Inconceivable, our last remaining airframe, crashed twice into the North Saskatchewan River in the days just before the AUVSI Competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-UVjnzF4vrpg/U6X44ycADJI/AAAAAAAAATg/qDnh90UarMU/s1600/WP_20140615_14_23_52_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crash #1, with the boaters that rescued Inconceivable for us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-AlVd6IcR444/U6X44iVIIhI/AAAAAAAAATc/bFAuvgu1wdc/s1600/WP_20140616_20_29_50_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crash #2, when we weren’t so lucky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The causes of the crashes are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Crash 1: Inconceivable has flaperons that were engaged on takeoff. These were not turned off after takeoff, meaning that the aileron servos could not move enough to have the plane bank as intended. The plane went into a severe right bank, lost altitude quickly, and crashed into the river. Thanks to the boaters in the picture above, we were able to recover the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Crash 2: When tuning a pitch control loop in AUTO2, Inconceivable went into a severe pitch down and gained a significant amount of speed. The pilot was not able to recover Inconceivable in time. Because Inconceivable was pointing north at the time this happened, it descended into the river.
These crashes were due to a combination of poor planning, a limited amount of time to tune and develop our autopilot, and pilot error. As a consequence, we have no functioning system right now, and are here at the competition as observers only.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been starting to think about our next system. Because of the crashes, we are in need of a new airframe and a new camera system altogether. The EPP FPV airframe we previously had is out of stock, and we have been thinking about replacing our camera system for a while. Some ideas that have been floated for each of these include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A small foam delta wing airframe. We’ve had good experiences with Murphy and Inconceivable, our two EPP FPV foam aircraft. Foam offers less weight and cheaper and easier repairs in case of a crash. We’ve seen 3 separate teams here with very similar delta wing models, and have been talking to them about their experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another scientific imaging camera (with a wider-angle lens that what we had).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A DSLR or other Canon/Nikon consumer camera running with a tethered shooting software, so that we can read live images from the camera.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A smartphone camera, with image processing happening on the phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to the awards banquet tonight; there will be a post later today about some of the events of the competition, as well as the competition results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition Round Up and Proof of Flight</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/06/05/canadian-competition-round-up-and-proof.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/06/05/canadian-competition-round-up-and-proof</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So here are a few pictures from Canadian competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YMOr4gqR51Y/U352Msn8eFI/AAAAAAAA
AQ8/b9aKwUkxvr8/s1600/5851.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YMOr4gqR51Y/U352Msn8eFI/AAAAAAAAAQ8/b9aKwUkxvr
8/s1600/5851.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-07iU4cTlQuM/U352Nn7NdFI/AAAAAAAA
ARI/ApZoyXa12qc/s1600/5854.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-07iU4cTlQuM/U352Nn7NdFI/AAAAAAAAARI/ApZoyXa12q
c/s1600/5854.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-KQ2_ui9eyGA/U352acAWu9I/AAAAAAAA
ARs/1ecDPaqsO70/s1600/5861.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-KQ2_ui9eyGA/U352acAWu9I/AAAAAAAAARs/1ecDPaqsO7
0/s1600/5861.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QyUfCVQiDO0/U352T27EPOI/AAAAAAAA
ARc/Qk10oSY9pk4/s1600/5870.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QyUfCVQiDO0/U352T27EPOI/AAAAAAAAARc/Qk10oSY9pk
4/s1600/5870.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-
mQQ3wWSmudE/U352SaluGlI/AAAAAAAAARU/AtvuocbTq8U/s1600/5867.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-mQQ3wWSmudE/U3
52SaluGlI/AAAAAAAAARU/AtvuocbTq8U/s1600/5867.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iGzk5LkcV3A/U352XLMgySI/AAAAAAAA
ARk/Owrr_ULGAf4/s1600/5877.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iGzk5LkcV3A/U352XLMgySI/AAAAAAAAARk/Owrr_ULGAf
4/s1600/5877.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-BGIYbjx3EnE/U5D27o3UI7I/AAAAAAAA
ASc/Zp2_T2O2Gtc/s1600/5475.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-BGIYbjx3EnE/U5D27o3UI7I/AAAAAAAAASc/Zp2_T2O2Gt
c/s1600/5475.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-
lA2GKQ0cGVc/U5D26NnbT1I/AAAAAAAAASY/BJFssA8ot-Y/s1600/5472.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lA2GKQ0cGVc/U5
D26NnbT1I/AAAAAAAAASY/BJFssA8ot-Y/s1600/5472.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ESPDAgcEdDs/U352eEc1iXI/AAAAAAAAAR0/o_QCE-
_Lu8U/s1600/6238.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ESPDAgcEdDs/U352eEc1iXI/AAAAAAAAAR0/o_QCE-
_Lu8U/s1600/6238.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZA-
BuNm2GM0/U352ejnwAaI/AAAAAAAAAR4/MGmpg-NjoQA/s1600/6241.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZA-BuNm2GM0/U352ejnwAaI/AAAAAAAAAR4/MGmpg-
NjoQA/s1600/6241.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team UAARG is way more mature than Murphy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally here is a proof of flight video of our system we are taking to US
competition.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition, Day 4</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/05/canadian-competition-day-4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/05/canadian-competition-day-4</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning, Team Murphy flew. They were able to capture images and
everything seemed well. Unfortunately midway through the flight their plane
experienced a loss of R/C signal, and nose-dived into the ground from upwards
of 50 meters. This was their last time to fly and the crash occurred during
the early portion of the flight. As a result, they were not able to geo
reference or visually spot any of the targets. Team Murphy was in high spirits
despite this, and are raring to rebuild their system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Y39Hr7bBqsY/U2dr72K-
rxI/AAAAAAAAAQQ/8uuwJAOztY4/s1600/WP_20140504_08_06_11_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Y39Hr7bBqsY/U2dr72K-
rxI/AAAAAAAAAQQ/8uuwJAOztY4/s1600/WP_20140504_08_06_11_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Murphy looking chipper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imaging portion of team UAARG had a late night last night. On the drive to
Manitoba, we lost our single SD card containing our operating system running
our imaging software. We had another, older backup; the imaging team stayed up
to troubleshoot and try to get to a functional system. On the flight line,
though, we had issues connecting to the onboard camera. Of the 40 minute time
limit for our flying, we spent the first twenty trying to get good data from
the camera again. Finally at the twenty minute mark we decided to just go with
a quick RC flight. The RC flight performed far better than expected. The
airframe and electronics were fairly untested and untrimmed but the plane
handled with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we brought the plane back to the ground, the imaging systems still
weren’t working. Our camera wasn’t having data being read from it at all.
Rijesh came up with the idea to donate his phone as a camera for the flight; a
minute and lots of tape later, we were ready to go up. We did a quick 2 minute
flight of the search area with the phone precariously taped in, just in the
nick of time for the mission to end. We were super excited to review the video
once we got back to the pits; lo and behold, we caught three targets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-k9uMkWZD9vM/U2dsCNKd
09I/AAAAAAAAAQY/uI9VU0Hs7Rc/s1600/Screenshot+\(8\).png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-k9uMkWZD9vM/U2dsCNKd09I/AAAAAAAAAQY/uI9VU0Hs7R
c/s1600/Screenshot+\(8\).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locations of the 3 targets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-a7zgoYJDQy4/U2dta26l
pkI/AAAAAAAAAQs/kdZmZLW_siA/s1600/Screenshot+\(7\).png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-a7zgoYJDQy4/U2dta26lpkI/AAAAAAAAAQs/kdZmZLW_si
A/s1600/Screenshot+\(7\).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture of the tent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our flight, Arshad reconnected our camera and we were successfully able
to run our imaging software and retrieve pictures encoded with geo-referencing
data. Essentially, we managed to get all our systems fully functional and
operational just as our mission timed out; our jerry-rigged system was that
was put together just 2 days prior was functional and back to its original
state! We pieced together our report with the data that we had captured,
submitted it, and were done with the competition! We were all pretty thrilled
and excited with our successes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The awards banquet was a pile of fun, as always, with a nod by the organizers
to the U of A teams’ open, fun, and relaxed attitudes. (The precise term used
to describe Team Murphy was “ballsy.”) Neither UAARG nor Team Murphy placed,
but we were able to get some prize money. It’s not easy to get 100 people who
are all interested in UAVs gathered in one room together, so we made the most
of our time chatting with the organizers &amp;amp; judges &amp;amp; other teams and traded
some contact information. The quality bar definitely seems to getting higher
and higher each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been an exhilarating past couple of days. Let’s close this post here with
an amazing shot of the Northern Lights that we were able to witness last
night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vqvFyArNjVs/U2dsE7TS1AI/AAAA
AAAAAQg/YWgywSP5-tA/s1600/P5030013.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vqvFyArNjVs/U2dsE7TS1AI/AAAAAAAAAQg/YWgywSP5-t
A/s1600/P5030013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that Arshad or Usain Bolt? We can’t tell either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk to you soon!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition, Day 3</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/03/canadian-competition-day-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/03/canadian-competition-day-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With a pretty good night of sleep behind us, we trekked out to the pits. We were
pretty burnt out the night before, but we had discovered a couple of problems:
our wireless router was not turning on inside our hastily-reconstructed
avionics box, and we had lost the SD card for the Pandaboard, taking all of
our files with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a look at the wireless router in the morning, and soon found out that
some of the voltage regulators we installed on the outside of the avionics box
were burning hot. We soon found that our router was shorting up against our
metal box, explaining our issues. We also had a fun scavenger hunt for the
Pandaboard SD card, but this turned up nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first flight time came up a bit sooner than we expected. We had some
trouble installing our avionics box inside the plane and so carved away a good
10 minutes of our 45-minute flight time. Once we were there, the first
priority was to get an R/C flight in, since the system hadn’t left the ground
since the crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we missed the same requirement this time that we did yesterday
during our first Flight Readiness go-around: the throttle would not turn off
if we lost the R/C link. As our flight time rolled on, we began to have more
inexplicable issues: we had a weak R/C link, our telemetry link died, etc. Our
time passed, and the plane hadn’t left the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to have Julien from VAMUdeS, who were running a TWOG and
PPM encoder system set up for their autopilot (just like us) help us out with
the last failsafe condition; once we had that and tested it, our plane was
ready to go. We were ready, but the weather wasn’t: it started snowing
outside, delaying our second flight to tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was plenty of stuff to work on once we got back: going out and buying
parts, restoring a backup of the Pandaboard’s card, replacing our voltage
regulators, debugging the imaging software, etc. Mostly, though, it was a lot
of sitting around and waiting. Here’s some pics of that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-fGM-MZpQWhE/
U2WYzpYLNsI/AAAAAAAAAPs/tI2S95hyYRQ/s1600/WP_20140503_18_05_56_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-fGM-MZpQWhE/U2WYzpYLNsI/AAAAAAAAAPs/tI2S95hyYR
Q/s1600/WP_20140503_18_05_56_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy Xiao&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Um44swkN14A/
U2WYyX_yalI/AAAAAAAAAPk/WUK_q9-94ik/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_15_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Um44swkN14A/U2WYyX_yalI/AAAAAAAAAPk/WUK_q9-94i
k/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_15_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arshad Husain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-XQFr_-
m6Quc/U2WYxeLHInI/AAAAAAAAAPg/F0LBbmroHvk/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_23_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-XQFr_-
m6Quc/U2WYxeLHInI/AAAAAAAAAPg/F0LBbmroHvk/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_23_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew Jowsey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FHOoRLatH74/
U2WY06QYVWI/AAAAAAAAAP4/k3s9te2oJ8Y/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_39_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FHOoRLatH74/U2WY06QYVWI/AAAAAAAAAP4/k3s9te2oJ8
Y/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_39_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Pollock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lCkBw_o2SYE/
U2WY1x4llnI/AAAAAAAAAP8/BzPcSqP93-I/s1600/WP_20140503_18_07_03_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lCkBw_o2SYE/U2WY1x4llnI/AAAAAAAAAP8/BzPcSqP93-
I/s1600/WP_20140503_18_07_03_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rijesh Augustine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Team Murphy side, they were out bright and early this morning - even
more so than expected because of a crash from UVictoria beforehand. Because of
a configuration mix-up, they weren’t able to get any pictures from their
flight today. However, that was a quick fix, and the rest of their system was
working perfectly well - lots of time to kill. Several hours of tomfoolery
later, they made this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-
cloYjgX9kJI/U2WYISuJnoI/AAAAAAAAAPY/Y-f55N8MAcA/s1600/Screen+Shot+2014-05-03+a
t+7.08.52+PM.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cloYjgX9kJI/U2WYISuJnoI/AAAAAAAAAPY/Y-f55N8MAc
A/s1600/Screen+Shot+2014-05-03+at+7.08.52+PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flight path of Team Murphy’s plane and locations of images they took&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is data of the test flight they did yesterday. The yellow pins are the
locations of the images taken during the flight, and the red path is the
flight of the plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, both teams are in really good spirits. Team Murphy has their system
entirely functional, Team UAARG is finally ready to fly. In addition to this,
we got to travel around a lot to the other teams’ pits to learn more about
their systems and share our woes. Interestingly, there seems to be very heavy
sponsorship of a lot of teams this year, with loads of donated commercial
hardware and imaging software making its way into teams’ systems. No matter
what the system, though, everyone had issues with the wind or their RF links
or their failsafes - it ended up being only 4 of 11 teams that actually flew
today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight’s our free evening for hanging out. We’re going to hang out, rest up,
and get ready for the last day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-9X3naFt9E74/U2WXv
iUxy1I/AAAAAAAAAPM/WjcvC_jMw9Q/s1600/2014-05-03+19.18.07.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-9X3naFt9E74/U2WXviUxy1I/AAAAAAAAAPM/WjcvC_jMw9
Q/s1600/2014-05-03+19.18.07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Murphy. Paul doesn’t know how to feel about this.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition Day 2</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/02/candian-competition-day-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/02/candian-competition-day-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 2 of our competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iE2mzHSlMyQ/
U2REy5M4eeI/AAAAAAAAAO0/X5iTxdGpL2s/s1600/WP_20140502_17_15_29_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iE2mzHSlMyQ/U2REy5M4eeI/AAAAAAAAAO0/X5iTxdGpL2
s/s1600/WP_20140502_17_15_29_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived safely last night/this morning at 1:00am. The ride was filled with
coding, learning and all-around competition preparation. As per our previous
blog post, you may be aware that we had a few issues with our airframe,
specifically the part when we decided to take it for a dip. Some quick
executive decisions were made to purchase replacement parts and our entire lab
was brought along with us to Manitoba. So at 1:00am there we were setting up
our lab in one of the rooms. Exhibit A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-6nOR6KMOSAE/U2RDirwJv8I/AAAAAAAAAOk/Nr-
DB32a9Ww/s1600/WP_20140502_03_02_39_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-6nOR6KMOSAE/U2RDirwJv8I/AAAAAAAAAOk/Nr-
DB32a9Ww/s1600/WP_20140502_03_02_39_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Busy away. Slowly one by one we fell and gave in to sleep. The majority of
Team UAARG getting less than an hour of sleep. Going to bed a 6:00 and waking
up at 7:00. Later this morning, the one time you can say that, we got up and
presented our project proposal. At this competition, we are “contracted” to
perform aerial surveillance, georeference targets, and calculate areas. We
each spoke a bit about our respective fields with Cindy giving a general idea
of why they should choose us as opposed to our competition. Following that we
finished our final rewiring. At this point we were in a state where we could
successfully capture images and tag them with telemetry data. The competition
has a Flight Readiness Review(FRR). Basically a test we have to pass that
ensures we have proper safety features present. At this point we should
theoretically have passed the FRR but would have done so in a very round about
way. Instead we decided to perform additional modifications to take the system
to the very same level as the pre-crash plane. And that is just what we did.
The first time the judges came to see our test we asked them to give us an
extension, which they graciously gave. The second time the judges came by we
thought we had everything configured correctly, but missed a requirement.
Finally a third time we went out and passed the test with flying colours. Just
on the nick of time as well. We performed a quick range test and noticed we
were not receiving the same poor reception. It seems like our crash was caused
by the metal cowl we had installed on the previous plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all though of the 11 teams only 2 teams actually flew today. UAARG did
not manage to take our plane up for a test flight, but we were capable to do
so. Alas we readied our plane 15 minutes too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From two days ago we had a drenched box full of electronics and now we have
rebuilt the plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NcD-JsZlPNQ/
U2RH0c7iluI/AAAAAAAAAPA/58TM5tdsAo4/s1600/WP_20140502_17_14_51_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NcD-JsZlPNQ/U2RH0c7iluI/AAAAAAAAAPA/58TM5tdsAo
4/s1600/WP_20140502_17_14_51_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The big job was coming together as team, and you guys did that” – Joseph
Patton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the two teams that actually flew today, one was Team Murphy. Their flight
was welcomed with applause. It was very heavy winds and basic flight control
was very difficult. Thankfully they made it down in one piece. Murphy
retrieved some very good images from this flight and look very prepared for
the official competition. They also received two standing ovations for
Rijesh’s piloting, mostly because there were no seats. But still a standing
ovation.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition After a Lovely Little Dip</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/01/canadian-competition-after-lovely.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/01/canadian-competition-after-lovely</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So after a very lengthy period of not posting, it is time for Canadian
Competition again. Right now we are on our way to Southport, Manitoba, rocking
to skipping music tracks and testing electrical components. So why are we
testing components, well yesterday we decided to let the plane take a dip at
the pond adjacent to our flying field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-tQGKtS5-m6g/U2LnVe-p7pI/AAAAAAAAAOU/PRyzpM6u7xg/s1
600/lRpg0GdnpHArknGAKjeGTiGtdKk7QWgO2wwusmnrIWA.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-tQGKtS5-m6g/U2LnVe-p7pI/AAAAAAAAAOU/PRyzpM6u7x
g/s1600/lRpg0GdnpHArknGAKjeGTiGtdKk7QWgO2wwusmnrIWA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rijesh and Mark pulling the plane out of the pond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fun adventure pulling this fellow out of the lake. We were
experiencing intermittent Radio Control(RC) loss while in the air. Some on
ground range testing would have been wise, but fortune favours the bold.
Apparently not. The plane lost RC and crashed into the lake. Our Airframe is
in fairly decent shape. The landing gear is a goner but the plane took the
crash well. Our Avionics box filled with itself up with water. We have two
switching voltage regulators that were built as a capstone project, and
thankfully those shorted and blew up fairly quickly. Our telemetry radio has a
few scorch marks on it, so it is probably pushing up daisies. Apart from that
the rest of the electronics seem fine. Contrary to popular belief water isn’t
that extensively damaging to circuitry. As long as the water is not filled
with excessive dissolved solvents the water actually acts as an insulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Mark’s steadfast work, we have a second airframe ready to go. We
should be able to remake the Avionics box, with a few adjustments to
accommodate a new radio and possibly and new autopilot board. Our current
Autopilot board uses something called a PPM encoder which takes the signals
from all the channels of the RC receiver and converts it into a single pulse
signal. If this is fried we may or may not decide to transition to a Lisa/M 2
autopilot board. This board has a built in receiver. Using this board will
require us to reconfigure our autopilot software. Since we are not using any
autopilot stabilized flight, this would not actually benefit us. At this
competition, however, we were only planning on flying the plane via RC. The
original autopilot board without the ppm encoder will still allow us to fly,
take photos, geo-reference images, and monitor the plane’s telemetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back it seems like our intermittent RC issues may have been due to a
metal cowl we added to the plane. We have eliminated faulty hardware and brown
outs as possible causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, we are bringing a second team to the competition – Team Murphy.
They’re a subgroup of UAARG composed of fourth year students designing a small
lightweight UAV for their capstone project.      All fourth year engineering
students take part in a yearlong project, where they apply what they have
learned from a variety of their courses.    They had some very promising
results in there test flight yesterday. They managed to retrieve very clear
images and find some targets we set up on the ground, giving some good data
for the georeferencing part of their system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The van was just now filled with everyone on a laptop coding and working away
on something or another, save the driver.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll Incorporated Features</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/10/08/incorporated.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/10/08/incorporated</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Incorporated provides a great typography, responsive design, author details, semantic markup and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set customize post covers, and other things directly in the post front matter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;layout: post

title: Jekyll Incorporated Features
subtitle: &amp;quot;What&amp;#39;s in the box&amp;quot;

# Setup post cover image in /images/
cover_image: blog-cover.jpg

excerpt: &amp;quot;Incorporated provides a great typography, responsive design, author details, semantic markup and more.&amp;quot;

# Author details, including Google Plus authorship
author:
  name: Karri Saarinen
  twitter: karrisaarinen
  gplus: 100687498195339762535 
  bio: Co-founder, Design
  image: ks.jpg
  
# Keep it as draft, not published in index.html or feed.xml
draft: false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;configurable--code-snipped-highlighting&quot;&gt;Configurable &amp;amp; Code Snipped Highlighting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/assets/stylesheets/main.scss:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-scss&quot; data-lang=&quot;scss&quot;&gt;/* Bodytext font */
$font: &amp;quot;Droid Sans&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;

/* Font for headings */
$fontheadings: &amp;quot;Droid Sans&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;

/* Text colors */
$text: #21272d;
$textmuted: #848484;
$accent: #2077b2;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;config.yml:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;inc:
  # Blog Information
  title:        &amp;quot;Jekyll Incorporated&amp;quot;
  subtitle:     &amp;quot;Modern Jekyll based blog for companies&amp;quot;
  cover_image:  blog-cover.jpg
  
  # Company information
  company:      Incorporated
  url:          http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/
  facebook:     sendtoinc
  twitter:      sendtoinc
  about_link:   https://sendtoinc.com/about/
  
  # Product Information
  product_link: http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/
  tagline:      &amp;quot;Get a modern blog for your company&amp;quot;
  
  # Comments
  disqus:
    # Eg. &amp;quot;exampleblog&amp;quot; Set to false to disable comments
    shortname:  false
  
  
  # Sharing settings
  sharing:
    twitter:    false
    facebook:   false
    gplus:      false
    hn:         false
    
  
 # Analytics     
  analytics:
    google: 
      # eg. &amp;#39;UA-123-12&amp;#39;
      id:       false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoomable images&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;full zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/incorporated.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awesome quotes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Effective companies tend to communicate more, their people are curious and they have opinions”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AUVSI SUAS Competition part 2</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/06/22/auvsi-suas-competition-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/06/22/auvsi-suas-competition-part-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been an eventful, stressful, and exciting few days for us at the AUVSI
SUAS competition;  we’ve  finally finished with all things competition and are
totally ready to get some much-needed sleep. We placed 23rd overall out of a
total of 33 teams at the competition. We received a $400 cash prize, and our
oral presentation scored fairly high at a position of 15th, beating the first
place team who got 18th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day one of the competition was mostly getting setup and tested to be certified
to fly. As we started the day, we were dedicated mostly to our last minute
preparations to our Flight Readiness Review. The FRR was the oral presentation
component of the competition; we were required to go over an overview of our
system, our safety measures, and the results of our systems testing. In the
end, we were able to prepare a nice, organized 15 minute presentation that
closely followed the requirements for the review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another crucial task on day one was the setup of the autopilot system; this
included setting up the failsafes and defining the search areas and boundaries
of the field. One component of the competition was navigating the plane
through a series of waypoints, and so these also had to be plotted. As we did
not feel comfortable flying in fully autonomous mode, our plan was to have
Cameron (our safety pilot) navigate using stabilized flight mode through these
waypoints, then fly a pattern over the search area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day two was when flights started. We arrived early in the morning to set up
our system and make small improvements. T  here were, of course, various
issues that popped up throughout the day. Under the heat, the epoxy glue
holding the elevators melted, and we had to quickly remove and repair the
elevators. We also worked on creating a better image geolocation algorithm;
throughout the day, we were in a rush to finish things because we weren’t
certain how long the other teams would take for their flights and when we
would be up for ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around 5:00 PM on day two after around 23 teams had flown, they announced
that the remaining teams would fly the next day and that we were in the first
four.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally received our chance to go out and fly on Saturday. Each team was
given one chance to complete a mission flight time of 40 minutes. As soon as
we arrived at the field we set up our system for our flight.  Somewhere within
the frantic activities of assembling the plane and taking it out to the flight
area, the XTend transmitter lost it’s ability to transmit past 10 meters. We
made our way out onto the air strip, setup the ground and imaging stations,
the mission time started, and we commenced our pre-flight checks, only to
discover the fault in the XTend radio. 17 minutes and 33 seconds into the
mission time, Cameron requested a timeout, which was granted. Arshad, Sheldon,
and Cameron took off to the nearby St Mary’s College campus to see what was
wrong with the radio without interfering with other team’s radio
transmissions. After much troubleshooting and testing, the problem was
diagnosed: the RF cable connector between the Xtend radio and the antenna was
causing attenuation, so was swapped out with a new XTend module which has an
RP-SMA connector to allow a direct antenna, foregoing the problem-ridden
cable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/c6qbwdu5iiFHaBlquTs4D0np4MUH2bPimM
ygCXWYeUdvRJ5eUrD9wT9JI0-l8kXbLr1G9Hn8M4hdWUtyIA_nn3s52IvDaAHmmJGvUKffalUW3jBK
Hi6iC0z8jg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/c6qbwdu5iiFHaBlquTs4D0np4MUH2bPimMygCX
WYeUdvRJ5eUrD9wT9JI0-l8kXbLr1G9Hn8M4hdWUtyIA_nn3s52IvDaAHmmJGvUKffalUW3jBKHi6i
C0z8jg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The XTend radio we’ve been using reliably for many months&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a remaining mission time of 22 minutes, we hustled out into the field for
our second flight. We soon got the entire system up and running: telemetry,
R/C, and Wi-Fi links were all functional at the beginning of the flight, and
images were being successfully transferred and displayed. However, immediately
upon taking off we noticed that the elevator neutral was much too far down.
This was because we had to replace it the previous day since the epoxy holding
the elevators together softened up in the heat and we obviously mis-estimated
the proper neutral. After landing and adjusting the servo positions, we took
off to make the most of our remaining 12 minutes of flight time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this flight, we noticed that images were coming in at a very sporadic
rate, and that only a limited number of images were being transferred. Most of
these images were of locations near the runway, and none of them contained a
target. The Wi-Fi connection from the onboard Pandaboard to the ground imaging
computer was spotty all throughout the flight, which caused certain photos to
fail to transfer. After our landing, we tried to transfer the images directly
from the Pandaboard to our ground station, but there was too little time to do
so and to obtain the target information for the judges; in the end, we handed
in a blank target sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com
/bbySGs9VKmkJfbRzTMC3SqoSPzIXy7O80tMkXHebYRC8_QTsx60xCJdfd-
PuYMjyy2CLESZhapp0WMaTvx9PJi9boU8Hw11ZmKIizi_0hVqrnUJpxLnlwAIKMw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our flight path including elevation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the problems with the flight and the different parts of the plane, we
still got some amazing data: alot of the search area was covered by Cameron’s
impeccable piloting, and a lot of the targets were captured by the plane. GPS
and altitude of the plane were recorded beautifully by paparazzi, and we were
able to export the data to google earth, where we were treated with a 3D model
of the planes path around the flight area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sIVkX39wzew/UcZxez5oIHI/AAAAAAAAAI
o/VjpBeLi0hAs/s1600/507.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sIVkX39wzew/UcZxez5oIHI/AAAAAAAAAIo/VjpBeLi0hA
s/s320/507.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cross with I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-raRTxUE9jRA/UcZxf6hkZaI/AAAAAAAAAJ
Q/XiI1KpNQd54/s1600/517.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-raRTxUE9jRA/UcZxf6hkZaI/AAAAAAAAAJQ/XiI1KpNQd5
4/s320/517.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pop up target?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iqGH8Vga0_4/UcZxgtCJrAI/AAAAAAAAAJ
o/1nKRTn26t8o/s1600/543.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iqGH8Vga0_4/UcZxgtCJrAI/AAAAAAAAAJo/1nKRTn26t8
o/s320/543.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue Star with 0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-yLUAcsDdais/UcZxhL96fnI/AAAAAAAAAJ
8/vsRvjhlqEFw/s1600/560.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-yLUAcsDdais/UcZxhL96fnI/AAAAAAAAAJ8/vsRvjhlqEF
w/s320/560.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is this the pop up target?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nG20f_8G6vE/UcZxh7Ga4lI/AAAAAAAAAK
c/5BHvQWEG2XY/s1600/597.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nG20f_8G6vE/UcZxh7Ga4lI/AAAAAAAAAKc/5BHvQWEG2X
Y/s320/597.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quarter Circle with a B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-N-L3jKwEnOo/UcZxkdxtt1I/AAAAAAAAAL
o/kfzBE8k8HVI/s1600/704.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-N-L3jKwEnOo/UcZxkdxtt1I/AAAAAAAAALo/kfzBE8k8HV
I/s320/704.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;White Sqare with T&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IbqZ3-Bsc-M/UcZxlNDUJeI/AAAAAAAAAM
I/P0wEzj8BzcI/s1600/753.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IbqZ3-Bsc-M/UcZxlNDUJeI/AAAAAAAAAMI/P0wEzj8Bzc
I/s320/753.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rectangle with N&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FMNxd5LLpqE/UcZxlpgDwsI/AAAAAAAAAM
c/Ekae_9bPb5E/s1600/850.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FMNxd5LLpqE/UcZxlpgDwsI/AAAAAAAAAMc/Ekae_9bPb5
E/s320/850.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here are what some of these targets look like on the ground:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9LMy77tWKB
w/UcX_F0QwJgI/AAAAAAAAI6A/fIl_SZa5jzY/w680-h510-no/IMG_20130622_130652.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9LMy77tWKBw/UcX_F0QwJgI/AAAAAAAAI6A/fIl_SZa5jz
Y/w680-h510-no/IMG_20130622_130652.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6dJdjSJ2Ilw/UcX-40XCe_I/AAAAAAAAI5o/tOmw6JmV-
cg/w680-h510-no/IMG_20130622_130639.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6dJdjSJ2Ilw/UcX-40XCe_I/AAAAAAAAI5o/tOmw6JmV-
cg/w680-h510-no/IMG_20130622_130639.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-c4ps4GK9wY
Q/UcX_mk4xa6I/AAAAAAAAI6w/8HCd_QNNw94/w737-h553-no/IMG_20130622_130716.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-c4ps4GK9wYQ/UcX_mk4xa6I/AAAAAAAAI6w/8HCd_QNNw9
4/w737-h553-no/IMG_20130622_130716.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still need to take a closer look at our GPS data to see how accurately we
might have located these targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, although we didn’t perform as well as we wanted to at this
competition we believe that we’ve made significant progress this year and are
looking forward to further development over the summer and through 2013-2014
for next year’s competitions. We’ll continue to work on stuff, seek new
members, and update this blog as we rise to meet the many more challenges that
are sure to come.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AUVSI SUAS Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/06/19/auvsi-suas-competition.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/06/19/auvsi-suas-competition</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And here we go again…
competition #2: the Association for Unmanned Vehicle Systems International
(AUVSI) Student Unmanned Aerial Systems (SUAS) competition. This competition
is in Maryland in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning from our trip to Quebec, we arrived at the airport 4 hours early this
time. Because of this, and because the airport was practically empty - only
overnight flights were left - baggage check in went smoothly. Our crates were
68 and 70 pounds with the limit being 70. Some of our checked luggage was 48
and 49 pounds, with the limit (to avoid a fee) being 50. We had to show Air
Canada their own rules on maximum luggage size though. Before we did this,
they were telling us the maximum sizes to avoid the oversize fee as if those
were the absolute limits. They were very friendly and helpful though,
especially considering our complex situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re currently waiting for our flight which should leave at 1:00 am.
Hopefully we’ll get sleep in the air since by the time we get to Washington,
it’ll be 10:00 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vGquG8A2Zac/UcFQ6
AAcCGI/AAAAAAAAAHs/VplIdEd0PIo/s1600/IMG_20130618_235938.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vGquG8A2Zac/UcFQ6AAcCGI/AAAAAAAAAHs/VplIdEd0PI
o/s1600/IMG_20130618_235938.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy and Arshad waiting at the airport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for technical aspects, we’ve been working hard on our system for the past
month and a half. We did lots of flight testing, but damaged the plane twice
and spent a lot of time trying to get neutral IMU values. We’ve fixed our
plane and have relatively reliable stabilized flight, but haven’t achieved
fully autonomous flight yet. As for imaging, we’ve made a lot of progress.
Images are now reliably transferred over FTP and the ground imaging GUI can
load them up as they come in. We still need to work on our geo-referencing
algorithm. Pictures taken during flight testing showed that this can be off by
over 50 meters. We’ll be working on this over the next day or two as well as
enabling telemetry over Wi-Fi so that we can show off our redundant link
software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Ll9ed925-cE/UcFKjoF6SuI/AAAAAAAAAHc/2AXYew-
vwsA/s1600/IMG_20130516_202053.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Ll9ed925-cE/UcFKjoF6SuI/AAAAAAAAAHc/2AXYew-
vwsA/s1600/IMG_20130516_202053.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The damage to our motor after a failed takeoff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-NfO_fVot3jw/UcFKg
SgkeVI/AAAAAAAAAHU/Ez73iz5k99U/s1600/IMG_20130611_203803.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-NfO_fVot3jw/UcFKgSgkeVI/AAAAAAAAAHU/Ez73iz5k99
U/s1600/IMG_20130611_203803.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Duncan Elliott holding the plane while testing the camera configuration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking forward to arriving in Maryland (and the comfy beds in our
hotel) as well as the competition itself. Expect a new post around once a day
until the competition is done. Also, feel free to leave comments below, ask
questions, or initiate any other type of discussion. We’d love to hear who’s
reading this blog and are able to post specific content based on what you’re
interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-iZkoDRO8GhI/UcFRJ
JNX0nI/AAAAAAAAAH0/o1zJpnunRG4/s1600/IMG_20130618_235933.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-iZkoDRO8GhI/UcFRJJNX0nI/AAAAAAAAAH0/o1zJpnunRG
4/s1600/IMG_20130618_235933.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emmanuel looking forward to the hotel in Maryland&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition Flight 2 - Day 3 - USC UAV Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/06/day-3-usc-uav.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/06/day-3-usc-uav</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning, we were able to get out onto the field right away and perform a
range test. Soon afterwards, we began our second competition flight. We
brought a second router for this flight in order to set up a connection to a
computer that would display the GCS to the pilot, in an attempt to perform
stabilized flight out of the line of sight and thereby expand our search area.
The plane’s takeoff and flight were smooth, and the radio and telemetry links
to the plane remained connected throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-_PQtLWAmY2I/UYgt7AMx4II/AAAAAA
AAAGw/VAmeaHt4Idk/s1600/blogp1.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-_PQtLWAmY2I/UYgt7AMx4II/AAAAAAAAAGw/VAmeaHt4Id
k/s1600/blogp1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameron monitoring the plane down the runway, with the pilot GCS laptop in
front&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-wAaa9RlDcpU/UYguaxwgDdI/AAAAAAAAAG4/3e-
QB_V31E4/s1600/blogp2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, almost immediately after takeoff, we noticed that the wi-fi
connection between the Pandaboard and the ground imaging laptop was extremely
weak, and at one point, even disconnected entirely. This meant that we were
only able to wirelessly transfer the first few photos taken by the plane. We
continued with the flight because it was still possible to land and make a
direct wired connection afterwards to transfer the images taken. A few of us
hypothesized that there was some interference between the two routers, but it
was only after the plane landed that we discovered that the new router was
using the _ exact same frequency _ as the router used for the imaging  despite
being set to auto select an unused frequency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wAaa9RlDcpU/UYguaxwgDdI/AAAAAA
AAAG8/cs8iBFYoD1g/s1600/blogp2.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wAaa9RlDcpU/UYguaxwgDdI/AAAAAAAAAG8/cs8iBFYoD1
g/s1600/blogp2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the targets at the imaging station&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this, we were still able to get all the images that the plane took.
Here are a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-U7TwmsXP0tQ/UYgswg9kk0I/AAAAAA
AAAGo/OjvLR9HUsS4/s1600/blogp3.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-U7TwmsXP0tQ/UYgswg9kk0I/AAAAAAAAAGo/OjvLR9HUsS
4/s1600/blogp3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZrN4_wKeMJ4/UYgu14BCDVI/AAAAAA
AAAHE/sUdWJaMTp3U/s1600/blogp4.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZrN4_wKeMJ4/UYgu14BCDVI/AAAAAAAAAHE/sUdWJaMTp3
U/s1600/blogp4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there was no possibility of discerning targets from any of
these blurry photos. This was because we had made another critical mistake: we
had taken out the working camera used for yesterday’s flight and replaced it
with the other identical but unfocused camera. Therefore, during this flight,
we were unable to identify any targets.  With the wind picking up and dark
clouds approaching, competition flights ended during the morning, and with
that went our last chance to improve on yesterday’s score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon’s activities were a welcome break. Most of this time was taken
up by the Mini-expo, which was a chance for all of the teams to set up their
systems to show to the public, sponsors, and other competitors, and to go
around and talk to the other teams. Cameron tried to add telemetry over Wi-Fi
functionality to the Panda Board in order to show a proper demo of his
redundant link system, but there were problems setting it up. Nevertheless, we
were able to gather some interesting information about the other teams’
operations. We also got a chance to look inside the unmanned aircraft MISKAM
at its systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After packing up our aircraft and other supplies, we headed to the final
banquet for acknowledgments, congratulations, and finally the announcement of
results. All of the teams that were able to get airborne were also able to get
target information. It turned out for us that out of the three targets we
identified the previous day, only two were correctly georeferenced. Every
other team obtained more targets than we did, mainly by virtue of performing
more than one flight with collection of target data. It seemed that correctly
obtaining GPS coordinates was a problem for many teams; even the top team,
VAMUDeS, had incorrect GPS information for about a third of their 30 targets.
We were glad to still receive a $500 cash prize; we also obtained files with
the correct target information and locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One bonus during this trip was our reception of media coverage. A reporter
from Radio-Canada came to the airport yesterday to do a news story on the
competition, and she interviewed- us about our systems and out performance
during our first flight. Our team ended up receiving the majority of the
coverage of the news story; a link to it can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www
.radio-canada.ca/regions/saguenay-lac/2013/05/04/004-drone-competition-
universitaire-alma.shtml&quot;&gt; here &lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4m1biray2KY/UYgsdrKwEuI/AAAA
AAAAAGg/kCLTHyERX5M/s1600/IMG_0448.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4m1biray2KY/UYgsdrKwEuI/AAAAAAAAAGg/kCLTHyERX5
M/s1600/IMG_0448.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demonstrating our ground control station to the RDI reporters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alma was an incredibly hospitable place, and we had a lot of fun during the
competition despite encountering some pretty major obstacles. There are many
things for us to reflect on for the next competition, and an enormous list of
things for us to work on, including a better systems presentation, major fixes
for the ground imaging software, and more detailed pre-flight checklists. This
Thursday, we will be having a meeting at which we can work on these and plan
the next one and a half months until the AUVSI competition. Stay tuned for
more updates then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3awgW3f39Uw/UYgrxEffDsI/AAAA
AAAAAGY/7bdzj71LQRI/s1600/IMG_0945.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3awgW3f39Uw/UYgrxEffDsI/AAAAAAAAAGY/7bdzj71LQR
I/s1600/IMG_0945.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L to R: Cindy Xiao, Arshad Husain, Sheldon Marquis, Cameron Lee, Emmanuel
Odeke&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition Flight 1 - Day 2 - USC UAV Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/04/day-2-usc-uav.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/04/day-2-usc-uav</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After all of the troubles yesterday, today has been a breath of fresh air so
far. We got up at 6:30 AM for breakfast at 7:00 AM and start of round 1
flights at 8:00 AM. Of the ten teams, we’re last on the list to fly, so we
flew at around 1:00 pm. With the servos now adjusted properly (thanks to a
member from team VAMUdeS for helping with this), we had a great manual
takeoff, very stable flight, and even flew in auto1 (stabilized) flight for
extended periods of time. We were also able to take pictures and start looking
for targets. During our 30 minute flight block, we actually took off and
landed twice. During the first flight we lost our telemetry link to the
autopilot during takeoff, but it worked great during the second flight, so
we’re not sure what went wrong. Also, we lost connection to the on-board
computer while in the air, but re-acquired it after the plane came closer to
the ground station. We were able to view and look for targets, although our
ground imaging software wasn’t loading the new pictures properly, so we did
this manually using an image viewer. After our 30 minute flight period, we had
issues with the FTP transfer so copied the remaining images over via USB. We
then filled out our target sheet with the three targets we found and submitted
it to the judges (pictures of these targets to be added after the competition
is over).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zbNikZIGzo8/UYV3A
yHsRbI/AAAAAAAAAGE/2VWf3jwtVIQ/s1600/IMG_20130504_130349.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zbNikZIGzo8/UYV3AyHsRbI/AAAAAAAAAGE/2VWf3jwtVI
Q/s1600/IMG_20130504_130349.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy Xiao looking for targets during the flight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A portion of our flight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we consider this flight a success and are working hard to make our next one
even better. There are three things we’re working on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the FTP connection working reliable. As of this blog post, we actually think we’ve got this finished.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up a second autopilot GCS for the pilot to view the plane on a map while flying in stabilized mode. This should let us fly further away from the takeoff area to cover a larger search area. As of this post, the setup has been done, but the decision as to whether we’ll actually fly further away will be made during out phase 2 flight tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix the ground imaging station software so that we can load and view pictures. Or, if this proves too difficult, create a new, simple program that will convert the UTM location data into lat and long data automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been informed that the rest of phase 2 will start tomorrow, so that’s
when we’ll be flying next. this gives us the opportunity to fix our issues and
get a good night of sleep. As long as we don’t encounter any unexpected
issues, tomorrow should be a great day.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup and Flight Testing - Day 1 - USC UAV Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/03/usc-uav.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/03/usc-uav</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The morning today was mostly dedicated to assembly and preparation of systems,
our safety briefing, and our systems presentation. The preparation for the
presentation was done in a rush, and we did not go over the technical details
of our systems and our team’s project management as much as we would have
liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ran into a host of unexpected issues almost as soon as we finished
assembling our plane and avionics box; as a result, it took a good part of the
day to successfully receive and transmit data from the plane and demonstrate
our failsafes in order to pass our flight readiness reviews and be cleared for
flight tests. First, when we went to do our flight readiness review, none of
our kill switches worked – because the lack of GPS was already killing the
plane, but we didn’t realize this until later. Then there was a bad connection
in the IMU followed by a mysterious issue with one of the power supplies
within the plane cutting out. We don’t know yet whether this was a short or
some other cause, because when we disassembled the avionics box to replace the
power supply, it started working again and has been fine since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got to the field, we were able to perform a calibration of our IMU, a
demonstration of our failsafes, and a successful manual flight with
transmission of telemetry data. The flight, however, was not smooth; the
plane’s ascent was choppy, and the pilot (Cameron was barely able to control
it). After three failed landing attempts – one where the plane nearly exited
the flight area while at only 10 m, we eventually landed the plane with no
damage. We determined that the cause of this brutal flight was twofold: the
deflection of the elevator and aileron control surfaces was much too too high
(the deflections in these reached their maximums at only 50% input), and the
COG was a little bit tail-heavy. We were easily able to fix both of these
issues and should be able to fly properly tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work on imaging systems has also been encountering numerous issues, including
problems with wi-fi connection of the imaging computer to the PandaBoard,
offsets returned by ground imaging target selection algorithm too large to be
reasonable, and issues with loading images and data from watched directories.
As we now have basic flight functionality, we plan to focus most of our work
tomorrow on imaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictures and Video Below…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-l3bZsE5RBoc/UYVyPHGkHTI/AAAAA
AAAAFc/vhnKl0dqUVM/s1600/P5030008.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-l3bZsE5RBoc/UYVyPHGkHTI/AAAAAAAAAFc/vhnKl0dqUV
M/s640/P5030008.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xy4oX1RX7KQ/UYVyQTli6eI/AAAAA
AAAAFk/E36TXdRbEFU/s1600/P5030010.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xy4oX1RX7KQ/UYVyQTli6eI/AAAAAAAAAFk/E36TXdRbEF
U/s640/P5030010.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4rCJfPKLrP8/UYVySa5nalI/AAAAA
AAAAFs/N-3_RVnMW9c/s1600/P5030032.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4rCJfPKLrP8/UYVySa5nalI/AAAAAAAAAFs/N-3_RVnMW9
c/s640/P5030032.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qlbZHY7NBTs/UYVyThrvSnI/AAAAA
AAAAF0/IW4T2qEA4Jk/s1600/P5030033.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qlbZHY7NBTs/UYVyThrvSnI/AAAAAAAAAF0/IW4T2qEA4J
k/s640/P5030033.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 0 - Unmanned Systems Canada UAV Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/02/unmanned-systems-canada-uav.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/02/unmanned-systems-canada-uav</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good news - we have just arrived in Alma, Quebec for the Unmanned Systems
Canada Student UAV Competition. The past few days leading up to competition
have been both hectic and tiring as we struggled to get systems in good
working order, to pack our plane and tools, and to rest up to be in good
traveling shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NZW6qhOeaO8/UYM
88eLJvbI/AAAAAAAAAE8/lNWhMSbYyd4/s1600/IMG_20130501_162451_1.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NZW6qhOeaO8/UYM88eLJvbI/AAAAAAAAAE8/lNWhMSbYyd
4/s1600/IMG_20130501_162451_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plane disassembled and packed in its crate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met at the airport this morning at 4:30am and promptly discovered that one
and a half hours was not enough to make it to the gate at a comfortable time
for our 6am flight. Re-packing our spare items into checked baggage and
processing our two large oversized crates were both extremely time-consuming,
and we just made it in time for boarding. Fortunately, the remainder of our
trip by air to Montreal went well, and we were able to drop off our crates to
be shipped and promptly get our rental car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CNrB7PTju2E/UYM9M
J6LUbI/AAAAAAAAAFE/DRcvDHN9x6Y/s1600/IMG_20130502_054313.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CNrB7PTju2E/UYM9MJ6LUbI/AAAAAAAAAFE/DRcvDHN9x6
Y/s1600/IMG_20130502_054313.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameron and Sheldon feeling optimistic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_mLDx3TsYJE/UYM9TNgca-I/AAAAAAAAAFM/tV-
ybIt3YYo/s1600/IMG_20130502_144429.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_mLDx3TsYJE/UYM9TNgca-I/AAAAAAAAAFM/tV-
ybIt3YYo/s1600/IMG_20130502_144429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our crates, finally arrived at Montreal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major things that we got done during the trip was creating a
complete flight plan specific to the airfield in Alma. This included defining
the perimeter of the competition field in our autopilot software, determining
the flight altitude, and creating takeoff and landing waypoints. We also
worked on refining the ground station imaging system and on our Technical
Presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, we perform both our Technical Presentation and Flight Readiness
Reviews, both major contributors to our overall score. These are critical for
giving judges an overview of our systems and for ensuring flight safety prior
to the first day of competition flight on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Redundant Communication - An Improvement to Paparazzi</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/04/21/redundant-communication-improvement-to.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/04/21/redundant-communication-improvement-to</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a special post, written to describe the
redundant communication project being worked on by myself - Cameron Lee -
current president of UAARG. The goal of this project is to allow multiple
radio modems or other links be used between the aircraft and the ground
station in a redundant fashion so that even if one link is lost, communication
can be maintained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, the plane to ground component has been created and tested. This post
describes how to use it and how it works. The code can be viewed or downloaded
from github:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uaarg/paparazzi/tree/redundant_comms&quot;&gt; https://github.com/uaarg/paparazzi/tree/redundant_comms
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following video is a demonstration of the system working and the interface
that lets you monitor links. The sections below discuss the details more
thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redundant Link Demonstration for Papparazzi Autopilot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll assume that the reader is somewhat familiar with how the ground segment
of Paparazzi currently works. However, this information can be found on the
wiki, here:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://paparazzi.enac.fr/wiki/Overview#System_Architecture&quot;&gt; http://paparazzi.enac.fr/wiki/Overview#System_Architecture
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a block diagram showing how the plane talks to the various ground
segment programs (also known as agents):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8-YENO6LcN
s/UXMRpkJlx1I/AAAAAAAAEZQ/Z3XDrJCRzQs/s1600/Normal+Communication+Layout.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8-YENO6LcNs/UXMRpkJlx1I/AAAAAAAAEZQ/Z3XDrJCRzQ
s/s400/Normal+Communication+Layout.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paparazzi Ground Segment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ivy bus lets the programs talk to each other through the use of short
messages. The direction of the coloured arrows is key since it shows the main
flow of these messages. Next we have a block diagram of the redundant link
system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nx_p90B7FU4/UXMddbJ_gEI/AAAAAAAAEZg/qnbrS-
bS3l0/s1600/Redundant+Communication+Layout.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nx_p90B7FU4/UXMddbJ_gEI/AAAAAAAAEZg/qnbrS-
bS3l0/s640/Redundant+Communication+Layout.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paparazzi Ground Segment with Redundant Links&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we can see a new agent, the Link Combiner. We also see multiple
occurrences of the Link agent. When operating in redundant mode, each
occurrence of Link transmits the data it receives from the plane to the Link
Combiner instead of the Server. It does this by transmitting the received
telemetry messages within the TELEMETRY_MESSAGE message which the Server
doesn’t listen to. The Link Combiner on the other hand does. TELEMETRY_MESSAGE
messages are sent by each link and include the id of that link. The Link
Combiner listens to all of them and then transmits a single set of messages to
the Server with the combined data. This results in the Server and all other
ground segment agents (such as Messages and the Real Time Plotter) getting
their telemetry data from Link Combiner as if it was coming from a single
occurrence of Link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-use&quot;&gt;How to Use&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to implement redundant links using this code, there are three simple
steps to follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect the hardware - on the airborne side, connect the Tx of the autopilot to multiple radio modems. On the ground side, connect multiple modems as normal (using USB to serial adapters, or whatever).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch a Link agent for each modem. Use two new command line arguments: _ -redlink _ and _ -id. _ The _ -redlink _  flag tells Link that it’s one of multiple links. The _ -id _  flag lets you specify an integer number as the id of that particular link.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch the Link Combiner agent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following screenshot shows a setup with two links, connected to serial
ports ttyUSB0 and ttyUSB1, and with id’s 1 and 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4ytdpqXMHa0/UXMlR-
qGkbI/AAAAAAAAEZw/JO959QjWip4/s1600/Screenshot+from+2013-04-15+23_02_27.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4ytdpqXMHa0/UXMlR-
qGkbI/AAAAAAAAEZw/JO959QjWip4/s640/Screenshot+from+2013-04-15+23_02_27.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Agents Running in a Redundant Link Setup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interface&quot;&gt;Interface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the redundant link system is started (even if only one Link is used),
several changes appear in the GCS. This is achieved by the new message
LINK_STATUS which is sent by the Link Combiner. These new features are
designed to allow closer monitoring and better management of the link(s)
between the aircraft and the ground station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following screenshot clearly shows these changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jI
7EMZ_0614/UXMjlc1MoBI/AAAAAAAAEZo/LwOgVQN336o/s1600/Screenshot+from+2013-04-15
+22_59_01.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jI7EMZ_0614/UXMjlc1MoBI/AAAAAAAAEZo/LwOgVQN336
o/s640/Screenshot+from+2013-04-15+22_59_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we can see that there is a new page in the notebook named Link. This
page contains critical information for each link. More information can easily
be added, but for now, it shows the status of the link (just like the main
Link status indicator in the strip), the current ping time, and the rate of
received messages. So if one link is lost, it’s status indicator will turn red
and start counting up just like link 2 in the above screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we can see that the main Link status indicator that’s located in the
strip has been modified slightly. It now shows the ratio of connected links to
the total number of links. I.e. 3/4 means that there are four links and one of
them has been lost. Furthermore, the indicator will be green if all links are
connected, yellow if one or more are lost, and red if all links are lost. Once
all links are lost, the indicator will count up just like before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, alerts have been added to the console. Whenever a link is lost or
reconnected, a message will appear in the console stating so. Messages also
appear when a new link is added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;link-combiner&quot;&gt;Link Combiner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Link Combiner agent is written in Python. It receives messages from all of
the Links (when they’re in redundant mode), and outputs messages to the Server
and other ground segment agents. There is a bit involved however since the
Server and GCS shouldn’t be sent identical messages. I.e. if the plane sends a
message and it’s received successfully by more than one link, then that
particular message should only sent by Link Combiner once. This is a somewhat
tricky requirement since there is no guarantee that the message will be
received by all of the links, and it’s possible that the plane actually sends
a second message that’s exactly the same as the first. No extra info (such as
a time-stamp or counter) is added to the messages sent from the plane to the
ground, so the Link Combiner employs an algorithm to detect duplicate
messages. Testing has shown that for typical links, this algorithm performs
extremely well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The algorithm gives each link a circular buffer to store the last N messages.
When a new message comes in on a particular link, the algorithm first checks
if it’s already in that link’s buffer. If it is, then it’s obviously a new
message, so its removed from all of the other buffers if it’s in any of them.
Then, the message is sent. If the message isn’t already in the link’s buffer,
then it’s added to the buffer. After that, all of the other link’s buffers are
checked for the message. If it’s in any of them, then the message was already
received by another link, so isn’t sent. If it’s not in any of them, then the
message is sent. The following flowchart depicts this algorithm:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-G1LYSsliAiY/UXNBjHj9
3PI/AAAAAAAAEaI/hom9cRmd3jI/s1600/Algorithm+Diagram.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-G1LYSsliAiY/UXNBjHj93PI/AAAAAAAAEaI/hom9cRmd3j
I/s640/Algorithm+Diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Algorithm to prevent duplicate messages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the plane sends various, possibly identical, messages and the links gain
and lose connection, there is no guarantee that this algorithm will do a
perfect job of filtering out identical and only identical messages. Howeve  r,
in typical operation, it seems to work very well. And for the application of
displaying aircraft data, the  occasional  missing or duplicate message is
acceptable. There are only a few scenarios where the Link Combiner won’t
produce perfect results, and they should come up infrequently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A message will be sent twice if the buffer size is too small to hold all of the messages received from one link between that link receiving the message and another link receiving the identical message. When the second link receives the message that has already been received, if the original isn’t in the buffer anymore, than the algorithm won’t know it’s a duplicate message. This scenario should be considered whenever implementing a redundant link system. Partly because it is the most likely to come up, but also because if it does occur, then all messages will be duplicated. In order to avoid this scenario, you can set the buffer size as a command line argument of Link Combiner. To know what a good value would be, you can observer the Ping time and Rx messages/s of the links in the new Link page of the notebook. Calculate the minimum buffer size by taking the difference between the largest ping time and the smallest ping time and multiplying it by the largest Rx messages/s. Then apply a safety factor when setting the buffer size - 10 times the calculated value should be good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A message won’t be sent when it should be if the autopilot sends a message that’s the same as one it already sent (same name and exact same values) AND at least one link was lost between the first message and the second AND the link that’s receiving the second message doesn’t have the first message in it’s buffer still. That’s three conditions. If this happens, then the Link Combiner will see the second message as a duplicate of the first and will skip it. Only this one message will be missed though - it won’t start happening to all messages. Also, the data will have been data that was already received. So if it’s for example the battery voltage message, then it’s not a big deal to miss it. As long as there aren’t links rapidly being lost and gained, then this shouldn’t happen often. Note that as the buffer size is increased, I believe that this becomes more likely to happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. As you can see, this is just the first half to a completely
redundant communication system. Once the autopilot is programmed to allow
multiple datalink inputs, then a fully redundant, two-directional
communications system can be used with Paparazzi. Furthermore, additional
features could be added such as the ability to send different messages over
different links, or messages at different rates over different links. This
could all be configured in the Link page of the notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to contact me regarding this at cam.w.lee@gmail.com or through the
paparazzi-devel@nongnu.org  mailing list (include my name somewhere in the
e-mail so that it makes it past my filter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Cameron Lee&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying in the Snow</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/04/20/flying-in-snow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/04/20/flying-in-snow</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite a while since our
last post. Many of you can probably guess why… exams. As this semester comes
to an end, we’re all extremely busy with studying. Nevertheless, our
competitions are approaching fast, so we’re continuing work on our UAV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2LL-
VYAcTPk/UXI2-t50P_I/AAAAAAAAAEs/8QTaoLCUIOE/s1600/HPIM5304.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2LL-
VYAcTPk/UXI2-t50P_I/AAAAAAAAAEs/8QTaoLCUIOE/s1600/HPIM5304.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adjusting the Skis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went flying this Wednesday to test our autopilot. Our objective was to
perform a few manual flights to record the necessary data to start configuring
the autopilot for our Senior Telemaster Plus. Then, if everything went
according to plan, we would attempt stabilized (auto1) flight. Of course,
everything didn’t go according to plane. Because we had so many issues, here
they are itemized:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most of the picnic tables were buried in snow, so we had to use one located right next to a pool of water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The autopilot couldn’t receive a location from our new GPS. In fact, it didn’t receive any data at all. We figured this was a wiring issue, so just connected the old GPS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When trying to use X-CTU to set the power level of the ground XTend radio, we couldn’t connect. We eventually solved this by turning off the plane’s XTend - it was transmitting to the ground XTend and blocking our attempts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When attempting our first take-off, the snow presented enough resistance to keep the plane on the ground.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When attempting our second take-off (with new batteries), the propeller pulled itself off of the shaft.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When attempting our third take-off, the plane… took off. Wait, that’s not a problem, that’s a good thing. Let’s put it in a new section: 
Flight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a video of the flight. It was very bright out and the camera isn’t that
great, so it’s very poor quality, but anyway:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were able to fly for a few minutes and collect the key data needed to
configure the autopilot. Specifically, we’ll use the typical cruise speed, the
amount of throttled used at this speed, and other similar data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the successful flight (and landing), there was one issue while
airborne - the RC link to the aircraft was lost for a few seconds at two
different points. This is actually a very serious problem since the cause is
unknown and if RC is lost for more than a few seconds, the plane will most
certainly crash. Here are two plots from after the flight showing the points
where the RC link was lost:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Altitude and RC Status vs time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-EtaE8OgF-
vw/UXIyyG7EHII/AAAAAAAAAEY/eYBPzosEDLE/s1600/RC+Lost+Plot.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-EtaE8OgF-
vw/UXIyyG7EHII/AAAAAAAAAEY/eYBPzosEDLE/s1600/RC+Lost+Plot.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green: Altitude [m]       Cyan: RC Status [good (low), poor (middle), lost
(high)]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we can see that there were significant altitude drops right after each
time the RC link was lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RC Frame rate and RC Status vs time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Dovh1nr6joI/UXI1z
GXcf3I/AAAAAAAAAEg/RZ5ff_bodno/s1600/RC+Framerate+Losses.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Dovh1nr6joI/UXI1zGXcf3I/AAAAAAAAAEg/RZ5ff_bodn
o/s1600/RC+Framerate+Losses.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green: RC Status [good (low), poor (middle), lost (high)]     RC Frame Rate
[Hz]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we can see that the RC link was indeed weakening - as opposed to it being
a hardware failure or software bug in the PPM encoder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’re going to have to do some more testing in an attempt to fix this
problem. Over the next days and weeks, we’ll be working hard on this and many
more issues that are sure to pop up. Despite being busy, we’ll try to keep
making posts, especially once we get to competition, so stay tuned!!!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteering, competition planning, and slow but sure progress</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/03/22/volunteering-competition-planning-and.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/03/22/volunteering-competition-planning-and</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone’s back from reading week and into the home stretch of the semester,
and we’re gearing up to get to competition readiness! Recently, however, we’ve
also been showcasing our work to students, alumni, and the public at various
events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We volunteered to host a booth at the fifth annual CO2 Powered Drag Car Races
hosted by the Faculty of Engineering. UAARG members covered two tables with
posters, our airplane, the ground station and a flight simulator. The flight
simulator turned out to be very popular! Even the other clubs wanted to play
on the flight simulator! The event took place at West Edmonton mall on Friday,
March 15th. At the CO2 races, junior high students raced wooden cars powered
by CO2 canisters. Between races, students, parents and teachers visited booths
hosted by engineering clubs. The UAARG booth was buzzing with people
interested in our avionics box, computer simulator and the competition
airplane!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-MYrqDbWym5E/UU0v5lWqWWI/AAAAA
AAAAEI/ds3axz9ycK8/s1600/DSC_0472.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-MYrqDbWym5E/UU0v5lWqWWI/AAAAAAAAAEI/ds3axz9ycK
8/s400/DSC_0472.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UAARG’s Booth at the CO2 Drag Races&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were also present for both the Electrical and Computer Engineering and the
Mechanical Engineering First-year Nights, where first-year engineering
students have the chance to talk to faculty, alumni, and student groups of
their engineering field of interest before choosing what program to specialize
in for the remainder of their engineering career. Plenty of interested
students approached us; they were interested in everything from our plane’s
construction to how we each personally got involved with the club to the ever-
popular flight simulator. We also brought our plane and poster to the Faculty
of Engineering’s Dean’s Reception for alumni. Many alumni took a keen interest
in our project; we were asked some challenging questions about our plane’s
systems from some very experienced engineers, one of which had worked with
UAARG in the past!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the mechanical front this week, we completed our analysis of the center of
gravity (CG) of our airframe and its components. As the picture below shows,
we have taken the moment of each component measured from the CG of that
component to the motor mount wall as a reference point. From this data, we
were able to determine the CG of the aircraft which we need to have 32cm to
34cm back from our reference point. If the CG was too far back the airframe
would tail heavy and be very likely to stall and enter an unrecoverable dive.
If the CG was too far forward the airframe would fly nose heavy, requiring
more power to stay in the air and making landing nose down a more prominent
issue. The other benefit is that this allows us to track where our weight is
distributed and what will have the greatest influence on the CG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Moment=mass*gravity*distance
CG distance=sum of the moments/total mass*gravity
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iNd_642a0a0/UU0v57mBcsI/AAA
AAAAAAEE/lEUJqi4cYgQ/s1600/Capture+cg.PNG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iNd_642a0a0/UU0v57mBcsI/AAAAAAAAAEE/lEUJqi4cYg
Q/s400/Capture+cg.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pie chart of moments of the plane’s components about its centre of gravity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, we’ve been planning for our upcoming competitions in May and
June – the Unmanned Systems Canada UAV competition and the AUVSI Student
Unmanned Systems Competition. We have selected the attendees of the
competitions and are in the process of figuring out the logistics of travel,
boarding, etc.; stay tuned for updates as we approach closer to the
competition dates!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It's Reading Week!!!</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/02/18/its-reading-week.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/02/18/its-reading-week</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s finally reading week!!! A
beautiful calm in the center of the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been taking this opportunity to make significant progress. We had a work
session on Friday and another on Sunday. We’re having a Critical Design Review
on Tuesday in addition to our weekly meeting. We’re also volunteering at
WISEST on both Tuesday and Wednesday. Sometime near the end of the week we’ll
go flying to do some of our first autopilot testing and likely have a pizza
and movie night afterwards to celebrate the progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for what’s happened since the last post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Air-frame:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve finalized our design for stronger landing gear and have started
construction. The only part we have to build is a simple wooden structure
which connects the carbon fiber or metal gear to the plane. Hopefully it’ll be
done before testing later this week, but if not, then we’ll use the stock
landing gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autopilot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots has happened with the autopilot. We got our new PPM encoders in last week
and got them up and running with the autopilot right away. We’re still not
sure what happened to our old one, but the new ones are working great. For
those of you not familiar with it, the PPM encoder takes up to 8 PWM signals
from the RC receiver and converts them to a single PPM single which the
autopilot can understand. This is necessary to use a modern 2.4 GHz RC
transmitter with the Paparazzi system which was designed for older, analog
transmitters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-moLoDd3CH44/USKT2
hkUvrI/AAAAAAAAADg/RahBCTpR-O8/s1600/IMG_20130205_164150.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-moLoDd3CH44/USKT2hkUvrI/AAAAAAAAADg/RahBCTpR-O
8/s1600/IMG_20130205_164150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New PPM Encoders&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also configured Paparazzi to use a switch on the RC controller as a kill
switch so that we can bring the plane down even if all we have is the RC link.
Previously, we could kill the plane from the ground control station, but if
the telemetry link is lost then our only two options are to let the plane try
and fly itself home or to take over manual control. If the plane is at the
edge of visual range and there are issues with autonomous flight, then neither
of these two options are particularly appealing. For those interested in how
we did this, take a look at our git repository at &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/uaarg/paparazzi&quot;&gt; github.com/uaarg/paparazzi
&lt;/a&gt; . Or for the particular commit, click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uaarg/paparazzi/commit/2d9048ba2836bc3edd36863ccfe82
a94ae1704ef&quot;&gt;
here &lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not all we did with the autopilot. We also got our new XTend radios in.
These are the radios used to provide the telemetry link between the autopilot
and the Ground Control Station. They operate at up to 1 W on the 900 MHz band.
Configuring the new radios was simple because we saved our configuration from
before. We immediately then went out to test them again. The last time we
tested them, we couldn’t get them to work at more than around 100 m. However,
we were testing them using a loop-back on the autopilot side. Because of our
particular configuration which is optimized for high throughput from the plane
to the ground and low, but important, throughput from the ground to the plane,
we figured this testing procedure might be part of the problem. So this time,
we tested the radios using the autopilot and it’s Ground Control Station. We
went out to Quad to see if the radios would work at distances of over 100 m.
The image below shows the path the plane was walked through quad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iswfqLX9c5k/USKvk_LNVa
I/AAAAAAAAADw/v6fKTkDbFzs/s1600/Telemetry+Test.PNG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iswfqLX9c5k/USKvk_LNVaI/AAAAAAAAADw/v6fKTkDbFz
s/s1600/Telemetry+Test.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking through Quad with the airplane&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We lost signal after there was no more room to walk without buildings getting
in the way. We measured the distance to be 300 m (the yellow line). So it
looks like the link is working good. We’ll have to do further testing out in
the country to see if it can go 500 m or 1 Km or 4 Km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing we did with the autopilot was figure out a way to configure the
on-board radio with it still in the plane, connected to the autopilot.
Previously we’ve had to take it out and connect it directly to the computer
which has a hassle. Achieving this was surprisingly easy since Paparazzi has
code to allow the autopilot board to behave like a USB to serial converter.
All we had to do was flash the TWOG with this in the air-frame file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;firmware name=&quot;setup&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;target name=&quot;tunnel&quot; board=&quot;twog_1.0&quot; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;target name=&quot;usb_tunnel_1&quot; board=&quot;twog_1.0&quot; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/firmware&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the computer that’s connected to the TWOG’s USB port can talk to the
radio through the TWOG and we can configure the radio without removing it from
the plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-board Software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, we took a look at the on-board software to try and fix the
segmentation faults we’ve been having. With the Panda Board’s UART RX
connected to the autopilot’s TX we could how see the telemetry data going from
the plane to the ground. However, the segmentation faults continued. We then
configured the FTP server properly and tested that the Panda Board could
connect to it. Running the on-board code after this worked. So success!!!! We
still have work to do to get a fully functional system though. And we want to
re-factor the code to allow it to run even when all the parts aren’t connected
(camera, autopilot, FTP server, etc…).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>12/5/13 Meeting Update</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/02/05/meeting-update.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/02/05/meeting-update</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past 2 weeks have been relatively quiet, but solid progress towards our
goals of flight testing and systems testing in the field are being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing, debugging, and commenting code were done on both the ground station
and onboard imaging over the last few weeks with the aim of fixing some
persistent bugs and revising code for clarity. This week’s technical demo was
of the onboard camera:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pb2PZzbh8H4/URGlQ
NDcUYI/AAAAAAAAACo/O0XXURgA2Ak/s1600/2013-02-05+17.30.13.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pb2PZzbh8H4/URGlQNDcUYI/AAAAAAAAACo/O0XXURgA2A
k/s1600/2013-02-05+17.30.13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sheldon’s technical demo of the FPV camera with image on a small LCD screen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sheldon is planning to get the camera mounted to the plane as well as connect
it to the plane’s power supply in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the airframe front, the foam airplanes for flight testing are complete and
ready to fly. The team is continuing to try and find a suitable flying field
and time for the foamies. In the meantime, potential pilots are training on
the flight simulator:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-5rsyUnUiCZA/URGsU
GohHeI/AAAAAAAAAC4/rFoneP2GD80/s1600/2013-02-05+18.00.57.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-5rsyUnUiCZA/URGsUGohHeI/AAAAAAAAAC4/rFoneP2GD8
0/s1600/2013-02-05+18.00.57.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More flight simulator training with the R/C controller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iGmEDA0h42I/URGsU
B0d3eI/AAAAAAAAAC8/nlzy44DvunI/s1600/2013-02-05+18.01.22.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iGmEDA0h42I/URGsUB0d3eI/AAAAAAAAAC8/nlzy44Dvun
I/s1600/2013-02-05+18.01.22.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the completed foamies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also started work on prototyping a new design for the plane’s landing gear
mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J7fvdcnIrAw/URGu7jp-
F1I/AAAAAAAAADQ/ypuTMdwlvWA/s1600/2013-02-05+18.14.29.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J7fvdcnIrAw/URGu7jp-
F1I/AAAAAAAAADQ/ypuTMdwlvWA/s1600/2013-02-05+18.14.29.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justin puts his carpentry skills to use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This design is part of several changes we made to the landing gear to increase
overall robustness in the light of several accidents with the landing gear
that occurred during competition last year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First post, first meeting, and a preview of what's ahead</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/01/22/first-post-first-meeting-and-preview-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/01/22/first-post-first-meeting-and-preview-of</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new 2013 UAARG blog! Last Tuesday, we had our first meeting of
the new year, in which we discussed work that went on over the holiday break
and looked ahead at the final months of work before competition in May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached one of our major goals over the holiday season: completing the
Competition Paper for the Unmanned Systems Canada Unmanned Air Vehicle Student
Competition, the first of our two major competitions this year. This paper is
meant to be a document that outlines the design process of the aircraft and
describes its major components and systems, from physical construction and
flight to communications and imaging. The paper is also judged toward our
final score in the competition, so finishing it was a very large milestone, as
well as a large relief, for the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second major goal reached over the holidays was the completion of the
range testing for the communications systems of the aircraft. Several
different wireless links are required for both controlled and autonomous
flight, as well as transmission of images from the aircraft. The entire system
was taken outdoors under conditions similar to those at competition, and the
range and capacity of each of the wireless links were tested. Though there are
still some problems with communications, the majority of the systems are
performing as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-R_n04UyK-
yE/UP9PHrevPuI/AAAAAAAAAAs/3ldhmrdXhMU/s1600/IMG_20130105_134943.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-R_n04UyK-
yE/UP9PHrevPuI/AAAAAAAAAAs/3ldhmrdXhMU/s1600/IMG_20130105_134943.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-6nrCRC74u78/UP9PD-
gg2tI/AAAAAAAAAAk/3I1IyclqHJ4/s1600/IMG_20130105_144937.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-6nrCRC74u78/UP9PD-
gg2tI/AAAAAAAAAAk/3I1IyclqHJ4/s1600/IMG_20130105_144937.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--2gxIfcTL3w/UP9PJ
KsOUbI/AAAAAAAAAA4/IiRDqMaqdEY/s1600/IMG_20130105_144914.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--2gxIfcTL3w/UP9PJKsOUbI/AAAAAAAAAA4/IiRDqMaqdE
Y/s1600/IMG_20130105_144914.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some photos from the outdoor range testing, including a graph of successful
signal transmission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still, however, quite a list of items to be completed in the weeks
ahead, one of which is flight testing of foam model airplanes so that R/C
pilots can be trained for competition. This is a priority at present because
of the lack of flight training that the pilots have received so far (flight
simulators are fun but no substitute), and we’re going to find an indoor
flying field appropriate for this purpose next. We are also working towards
having a functional, testable version of the ground station imaging system in
a few weeks’ time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-V20pxL7F9Ww/UP9R5
qBK3HI/AAAAAAAAABM/-Sj_iuDICPc/s1600/2013-01-22+18.32.34.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-V20pxL7F9Ww/UP9R5qBK3HI/AAAAAAAAABM/-Sj_iuDICP
c/s1600/2013-01-22+18.32.34.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zg9ZkMExNO4/UP9R6
PXgy_I/AAAAAAAAABU/5azrZlKNn8g/s1600/IMG_20130122_185623.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zg9ZkMExNO4/UP9R6PXgy_I/AAAAAAAAABU/5azrZlKNn8
g/s1600/IMG_20130122_185623.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few shots of the foam airplanes under construction for pilot training&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stay on track in the meantime, we have set several internal deadlines for
the completion and testing of major systems before competition. We are also
piloting the idea of short presentations by one of the subgroups (airframe,
autopilot, imaging, etc.) at the beginning of each meeting; these are meant to
familiarize members with all aspects of the plane and its systems, as well as
update on progress in subgroups. Stay tuned for updates on the blog as we gear
up for the competition season!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    

  </channel> 
</rss>